[Music]
hey what's going on guys welcome to my
CSS crash course for absolute beginners
this is a continuation of my HTML crash
course in this video I'm going to try
and cram as much information about CSS
that I can starting from scratch and you
don't need to have any experience at all
whatsoever with CSS to follow along
alright so a few things before we get
started I want to stress that this guide
is for beginners and people that don't
really know anything about CSS it's a
continuation of my HTML crash course on
YouTube so unless you know HTML pretty
well I would suggest going back and
watching that video first and the link
is in the description alright now it's
important to know that when it comes to
CSS it's much more free than HTML
meaning that there's there's many ways
to do the same thing in HTML you have
specific tags that you use to create a
document while CSS is used for design
and layout so it's much more artistic
many advanced web developers still
struggle with CSS because it's much more
right-brain however when you're
following along with this guide you'll
notice that we're just we're going to be
looking at the CSS syntax not so much
creative and artistic abilities or
styling trends and stuff like that
alright so hopefully that makes sense
also we're not going to be covering more
advanced topics like flexbox and
animation flex boxes of css3 layout mode
and it does things like align elements
very easily but I think it's too
advanced for this video plus I do have a
video called flexbox in 20 minutes that
teaches you all about it so if you want
to learn more about flex i'd suggest
watching that after this all right and I
will be doing an advanced css3 video
very soon and that will include things
like animations and transitions you know
all the pseudo elements things like that
alright so we can't cover everything in
this guide this is a crash course but I
will be covering the most essential and
useful parts of CSS alright so let's
talk a little bit about what CSS
actually is it stands for cascading
style sheets and like HTML it's not a
programming language
it's actually a style sheet or a styling
language it's used for website layout
and design and it's used alongside of
HTML now it can also be used with other
mock-ups like XHTML XML SVG but it's
most commonly used with HTML now by
default CSS doesn't have any logic like
a programming language does it's
strictly presentational however there
are technology such as sass and less
that do allow you to extend the
functionality of CSS and allows you to
use things like variables and
conditionals but that's way beyond this
course oh just dude I did want to let
you know that that that is an actual
thing all right I do have videos on sass
and less on my channel if you're
interested so all you need to get
started just like when in the HTML crash
course we just need a text editor and a
browser we'll be using Google Chrome as
our browser and sublime text as the
editor I went through the installation
of sublime text back in the HTML crash
course so I'm not going to do that again
you can use sublime or you can use
something else atom in visual studio
code are fantastic editors but I do
think they're overkill for this this
particular video alright notepad plus
plus and text mate are also some very
simple and very light solutions alright
guys so we're going to go ahead and get
started let's create a new folder I'm
going to put it on my desktop and we're
just going to call this CSS crash course
alright now there's going to be two two
things that we're going to do first
we're going to build like a cheat sheet
like we did with the HTML crash course
where it's not really put together site
or anything like that it's just a way
for us to learn it's a way for us to add
classes and IDs and then go through all
the specific styling rules and stuff of
CSS and then after that we're going to
actually lay out an actual I wouldn't
really call it a website but I guess a
website homepage where we use html5
semantic tags and I show you how to
float things and and just create a basic
basic web page all right so let's go
ahead and create a new folder in here
and I'm going to call this CSS cheat
sheet
all right and that's what we're going to
be working with first but then I'm also
going to create a folder called my
website and that's what we'll be working
with after so for now we're going to
work in the cheat sheet so let's go in
there let's create our index.html file
alright and then what I'm going to do is
I'm going to open this up in sublime
text I'm actually going to open up
sublime and then I'm going to go to file
open folder and we're going to go to or
is it the desktop CSS crash course I'm
going to open that up and then you can
see I have both folders over here okay
so we're kind of treating these both as
different projects so we're starting in
the CSS cheat sheet so let's open up the
index.html and with sublime we can say
HTML tab and that's going to give us a
basic structure and I went over all this
in the HTML crash course so if you don't
understand what this is please go back
and watch that video so for the title
let's just say CSS cheat sheet alright
and before we write anything I just want
to go over the different types or the
different methods of using CSS so
there's three main ways of adding CSS to
an HTML file there's inline internal and
external I'm going to show you the an
example of all three but let's talk
about the difference first so inline CSS
means that you're adding a style
attribute to the actual HTML tag just
like you would any other attribute like
title or href this is not what you want
to do it's it's horrible practice and
you'll never see a professional web
developer do this one of the key rules
to follow as a developer or a programmer
with any language is to keep the
presentation the functionality and the
styling completely separate or as much
as possible using inline CSS is mixing
that presentation with styling and it's
not efficient it's not scalable and it's
just not practical inline CSS refers to
using style tags within the head of your
HTML page we did do a little bit of this
in the HTML crash course at the end and
this is a hell of a lot better than
using inline CSS because it does
separate the style from presentation but
it's still not too suggested method this
makes it so that the CSS that you're
writing can only be used in that
particular HTML file all right it also
fattens up the HTML file and you want to
keep it as slim as possible with just
HTML the third option is the best and
the most used and that's to use an
external CSS style sheet you can create
a separate file with a dot CSS extension
and then you can simply link that file
to whatever HTML file you want whatever
you want to use that CSS with all right
so we're going to be using the external
method and that is for the most part
suggested all the time alright guys so
let's go ahead and open up our index
file on our browser alright so we have
our CSS cheat sheet I'm just going to
open index.html which is going to be
completely blank
actually the title did I not save this
now I didn't save that so if I reload
now you'll see if CSS cheat sheet in the
title if I do a ctrl you you'll see the
source code which just matches what we
have over here all right so let's go
ahead and look at the different ways to
implement CSS so I'm going to put an h1
in here and we're just going to say
hello world all right so it was simple
h1 if I save and reload it's going to
show up on the screen now let's say I
want to just change the color of this
okay now the first way that I'm going to
demonstrate is inline CSS so that is by
using a style attribute and then doing
the actual CSS which will say color
read and save okay now that does work
but this is a horrible horrible way of
implementing this okay because we're
mixing the presentation which is just
the h1 and the text with the styling or
with the CSS which is this color red and
we don't want that we want to keep these
separate alright so that's the first way
and we don't want to use that way now to
to not use inline styling we need to we
need a way to grab onto this and we can
actually use the element itself a lot of
times we'll be using IDs and classes to
grab on to an element but you can just
use the actual HTML tag so let's take a
look at the second way which is internal
so for that we would put style tags up
in the head area okay you want to put
these in the head and then inside there
we can put our CSS so for instance that
we want to grab the h1 we can use that
out of the selector and then some curly
braces and then we can say color red
okay if I sit actually let's make it
blue just so you can see that it
definitely is coming from here so if I
reload now we get blue alright and like
I said this does separate per you know
presentation from style but you can only
use these styles within this file okay
you may want to use these in other HTML
files as well so that brings us to the
third method which is external so what
I'm going to do is go into our CSS cheat
sheet folder and create a new folder
called CSS and then this is where we
would put our style sheets
okay so let's create a new file and
we'll call this style dot CSS we gotta
save it ctrl s style dot CSS okay now
you don't have to call it style you can
call it whatever you want just make sure
it has a dot CSS extension alright and
then what we'll do is we'll say h1 just
like we did in style tags in the HTML
and we'll say color green alright and
then we'll save that now obviously
that's not going to work right now
because it doesn't know to even look at
this style sheet so what we're going to
do is get rid of the style tags here and
we're going to use an HTML tag called
link okay so we're going to say link in
sublime text we can just type the word
link and hit tab and that's going to
give us the tag along with some
attributes so it has this rel attribute
which is telling it that this is a style
sheet we also have a type which is
saying that this is going to be CSS and
then the href is going to link to the
CSS file so in here we want to say CSS
slash style dot CSS and the reason I put
this CSS slash is what is because it's
located in the CSS folder right here so
you have to specify the entire location
all right so let's save that reload and
now you'll see that it's green it's
actually looking
at this style.css file all right so
that's the recommended way to do it and
if we wanted to use these styles in
another HTML file all we have to do is
put this in there so let's look at a
quick diagram of a CSS selector and a
declaration so this is a basic format so
we have the selector here in this case
we're saying a so an 8 and a tag is a
link okay we learn that in the HTML
crash course now you can use the actual
element like this but what this is going
to do is it's going to apply this style
to all links everywhere if you wanted to
target a certain link you could use a
class or an ID okay we'll get into that
a little bit and then to start the
declaration we have an opening curly
brace to end it we have a closing curly
brace and then inside there we have a
property and a value okay so like a key
value pair the property is going to be
in this case background color and we're
going to go over a ton of different
properties that are available in CSS now
just to separate these we have our our
colon here and then we have the value in
this case we're saying the background
color should be yellow and then you
always want to end these with a
semicolon
all right so we're going to jump in and
start to create such styles here now I'm
going to go to the CSS file and get rid
of the h1 styling here okay and then I'm
just going to say body and then open up
some curly braces all right so we have
our selected here which is body this is
going to pertain to the body tag and
everything in it okay well I shouldn't
say everything and it's not going to
actually change like the background
color of every element but the body
itself which wraps around everything so
let's add a background color and I'm
going to change this to a value which is
going to be a hexadecimal color and I'm
going to go over this in a second but
it's going to be number sign f4 three
times so if we save this and we reload
notice that the background first of all
the green text went away because we got
rid of that style but the background of
the body is now light gray okay this is
a hexadecimal value for light gray now
if we want to change the color of the
text we can use the color okay so let's
say we want color to be the hexadecimal
value
of six 5s and that's going to be a dark
gray now if I reload notice that the h1
actually changed to a lighter gray so
any text we put in by default this can
is now going to be this color so just a
little bit about colors in CSS now we
can use different values here so we can
use color names we can use html5 color
names hexadecimal values and our RGB our
red green blue values so with this
example here we're using color names so
color red because blue yellow very you
know common colors and then html5 added
some extra colors here okay so for
instance coral which is like a light
orange and there's a lot of them there's
misty Rose there's all types of weird
colors that you can look up all right
now hexadecimal values look like this we
have the number sign and then you have a
code which pertains to that specific
color okay six zeros is going to be
black and six FS is going to be white
you can also use shortcuts and use three
about three characters as well for some
of these and I'll show you that in a
little bit and then we can also use RGB
values so we use RGB and then some
parentheses and then the value of red
green and blue okay so here we have blue
at 255 which is going to make this color
a certain shade of blue all right so
back to our HTML and CSS now what I'm
going to do is under the h1 I just want
to put in a paragraph and in sublime we
can type in the word larom and tab and
it'll give us a bunch of sample text all
right we'll reload that just so we have
some something else to look at so for
the body I'm also going to add I'm going
to change the font so let's say font
family and I'm going to say Arial and
then if for some reason Arial can't load
it's going to load what we put here
let's say Helvetica and then we're going
to do sans-serif all right so let's save
that and reload and notice that the font
has now changed now in CSS you have web
safe fonts and then you have other fonts
which you can use now web safe fonts
means that you don't need to improve
or any kind of special font you can just
use it just like we did here all right
if you want to use some kind of
specialty font from let's say Google
Fonts you'd have to bring that in like
you would a stylesheet and then apply it
all right so let's take a look at some
of the web safe fonts so here's an
example of the different font families
that we can use and we don't have to
import any kind of special font files or
anything so this is what we use the
arial helvetica sans-serif we also have
Arial black Bookman old style cause
Comic Sans courier which is kind of like
a Microsoft Word type font let's see
what else Georgia verdana is pretty nice
I like for Dan I like to Homa Times New
Roman which is the default if you don't
apply a font that's what the default
will be in most browsers and it's pretty
much it so these are the web safe fonts
and when we talk about serif fonts you
can see that the serif fonts have the
little little hooks on the end here of
the letters and then sans serif is kind
of a flat look all right so that's the
basic difference between those I'm not
an expert on fonts or anything like that
but I just wanted to give you guys an
idea of what's considered a web safe
font
all right so let's get back to our CSS
I'm just going to make this wrap so that
you guys can see everything we'll just
do word wrap and let's go ahead and add
a change the size of the font so for
that we can simply just say font size
and we'll set that to 16 pixels and if
we save and reload it's going to look
the same because that was actually the
default but if I wanted to change this
to let's say 12 pixels reload you'll see
it gets much smaller all right
now we can also change the font weight
from here so if we say font weight we
can set that to bold and reload and
it'll make everything bold you can also
use numbers like 400 you can change the
the boldness with the number as well but
we're going to we're going to keep this
at normal okay by default
now there's actually a shorter way to do
this when you're dealing with these font
dash styles here we can actually just
use font and then we could say normal
for the font weight and then we could do
the font family which would be arial
helvetica sans-serif and then we can
just put the font actually let's put the
size here so 16 pixels all right and
then if I get rid of these three and
reload we get the same thing okay so
it's just a shorter way of doing it let
me just put a little comment here and
I'm just going to say same as above all
right and you know I'm leaving all this
stuff here so you guys have this as a
reference normally you wouldn't have
both of these but I want you guys to
have this if you need it later on
okay another common style you'll see
within the body is the line height okay
now notice that these to me these these
lines look pretty close together so I'd
want to kind of separate them just a
little bit so what I'm going to do here
is say one point six M or e m and let's
save that reload and now notice that
there's this more space in between the
lines all right that's what line height
does now EMR m is just a unit to use in
in CSS it's usually used for more
responsive type websites you could just
make this pixels as well so if we wanted
to say three pixels for the line height
you'll see that there's only three
pixels in between which makes it
unreadable
but you can do that but we're going to
stick to M usually you'll see M for line
Heights alright so what I'm going to do
now is just add a little bit of HTML
over here some more HTML so let's go
actually know what we'll do is we'll
wrap the h1 and the paragraph in a div
and let's give that a class we'll give
that a class of let's say box - one
okay so wrap the paragraph and the
heading
okay we'll push that over a little bit I
don't like house yeah I'm just going to
make this a little bigger so let's talk
a little bit about the difference
between class and ID now as far as the
browser goes and enforcing rules ID in
class really there's no difference when
it comes to HTML and CSS but what you
want to do is you want to think of IDs
as elements that are IDs that aren't
going to be put anywhere else they're
going to be unique so for instance if
you have a main nav bar you might give
that an idea of main nav bar because
you're not going to be using that main
nav for our ID on any other element but
if you're using something like let's say
class box one where we're going to give
this a background color and a border and
stuff you may use this box 1 somewhere
else because you may want to apply that
style so it's not unique so you would
use a class if you if you had a class
that made text red or something like
that
you would want to use a class because
you may use that somewhere else so just
remember that IDs should always be
unique classes you can reuse classes all
right and if you don't want to follow
that standard I would suggest just
always using classes you'll notice that
with frameworks like bootstrap they
don't use IDs for anything it's all
classes you just don't want to repeat
IDs that's that's the bottom line
all right so we have this div with the
class of box 1 so let's go ahead and
save this and then we'll go into our
styling and let's just make this smaller
so to target a class we use a dot so
remember we called it box 1 so we're
going to say dot box 1 all right now
what I'm going to do here is I'm just
going to add a background color first of
all so let's say background - color and
let's set it to like like almost black a
dark gray which is going to be three six
times now this is one of those colors
where we can use a shortcut okay we can
actually use just three threes and it'll
give us the same color all right so
let's save that and reload and notice
that the background is now a dark
gray well one thing I also wanted to do
was on the body I want to zero out the
margin and I'm going to go over margin
later on so don't worry about that but
I'm just going to set margin to zero and
that'll get rid of these spaces around
it okay except for the top because
headings actually have margin by default
all right so we have this box one with a
background color of dark gray almost
black so we want to change the text
color because it's almost unreadable so
we're going to say color and let's set
that to white now we could do the text
white but I prefer to use hexadecimal so
I'm going to say number sign and then
three FS okay or six FS whatever you
want reload and now the text is white
now I would like to push everything in
from the edges and you'll see this a lot
usually with websites the content will
be pushed in it's not going to go all
the way up to the edge so what we can do
is create a class I'm just going to put
it right here and let's call it
container if you've ever used bootstrap
or other frameworks you just probably
seen this quite a bit and we can set
this to a width okay so for right now
I'm just going to say 500 pixels all
right and then let's go ahead and save
that and then let's apply that container
so let's wrap it around the box actually
I'm going to have this Raptor out
everything okay so we'll go down here
and put the ending div tag let's tab it
over all right so if we save that and
reload you'll see that it's now 500
pixels wide now with containers like I
said you want to usually want to push it
to the middle so to do that we're going
to just say margin and we're going to
set it to auto and what this does is it
sets margin it sets an auto margin on
all sides okay it's going to set it to
the same on all sides so let's save that
reload and it gets pushed over it puts
an even amount of margin on this side
and this side and margin is basically
spacing around an element now setting it
to 500 pixels actually you probably
wouldn't see 500 you might see like
960 is a popular width for a website
okay something like that but this makes
it so it's not responsive if I make it
smaller you can see that it's not
responsive it's not adapting correctly
so what we would do is set it to a
percentage instead of pixels so I'm
going to set it to 80% okay and then
reload and then as I make it smaller
you'll see that it actually responds
correctly to size so you for the most
part you want to use percents when
you're dealing with something with
containers or something like that
all right so now let's talk about margin
and padding so a lot of people get
confused at first with margin and
padding because both of them pertain to
space around an element so I'm going to
try to explain that the best I can so
there's something called the box model
in CSS and think of this content block
ads whatever your element is whether
it's a div or an a tag link or a
paragraph a heading anything at all and
padding is going to be the space in
between that element and its border okay
it's edge so that padding you can set
the top to the right the bottom or the
left padding to whatever you want
okay and it'll add that space now the
border has to do with the border
property and you're not always going to
be using this but you can set the border
width you can set that to the width and
you can do top right bottom left and
then margin is going to be the spacing
outside of that border okay so just
remember padding is the space inside
margin is the space outside now when
we're applying styles to or when we're
applying padding and margin there's
different ways to do it
okay there's there's the long way and is
the short way now in this example we're
using margin for this paragraph so we're
saying we want the margin top to be 5
pixels the margin bottom 5 the margin
right to be 10 and the margin left to be
10 so if we look at our box model here
it is the top and bottom margin that we
want to be 5 so it would be this in this
and then the left and right would be 10
okay now over here we have this same
thing in a shorter syntax so instead of
doing margin
top margin bottom and so on we can just
say margin and then we can do top top
right bottom left okay that's that's
what you need to remember top right
bottom left and you'll see top five
whoops top five right ten bottom five
left ten all right now to take it step
even from do you know to make it even
shorter if the top and bottom are the
same and the right and left are the same
okay
such as in this case top and bottom or
five left and right ten we can do this
and we can say five for the top and
bottom ten for the left and right okay
so that's a short of syntax and then of
course if they're all equal you can just
do margin five pixels and that'll add
five pixels around the entire thing and
you can use this same format with
padding you can do padding top padding
bottom and then same thing over here you
can just use padding all right so what
I'm going to do now is I'm going to add
a border to this just so we can see the
difference between padding and margin
more clearly so for box one here let's
go ahead and let's say border right okay
and we're going to set that to five
pixels red okay so with size color and
then type or style which I'll say solid
so let's go ahead and save that and
reload and you'll see that on the right
we have a five pixel red solid border
all right now if we wanted to add
borders on other sides let's say we
wanted to do left okay so if I save that
it's going to add it on the right and
left and of course we could do top and
bottom all right and that's just going
to give it a five pixel border around
the whole entire thing now just like
with margin and padding there's their
short hands you don't have to do all
this if you want them all to be the same
okay so what we could do is we could
just say border and then we could say
five pixels red solid
okay and then if we got rid of all of
this and saved it reload we get the same
thing so this is what you would want to
do instead of this but I'm going to keep
it there again just you guys have it and
say same as above all right now you can
also target specific border properties
like the size the color and the style so
let's say for instance we wanted to
change the width we could say border -
width and set it to 3 pixels and if we
reload that's going to set all sides to
3 pixels if we wanted to let's say just
target the width of the bottom bottom
bottom border bottom we could say border
bottom width and let's just set that to
10 pixels okay so we can target it like
that we can also do styles so if we want
to say like border
let's do border top style and we'll set
that to dotted so if I reload now you
see the top border is dotted and I
believe there's there solid dotted
dashed double I think there may be a
couple others so if you want to look
that up you can but for the most part we
at least for me I usually use solid
alright now I want to keep this very
simple and I just want to have this so
I'm going to put that right there and
that should overwrite everything okay
but again I am going to leave all this
just so you guys have it so now let's
look at padding okay so in here let's
say padding I will say padding top and
we'll set that to 20 pixels reload and
you'll see that it adds it to the top
now there was initially some padding
here because an h1 by default has
padding now if you wanted to you could
you could zero out the margin and
padding for everything on the page and
let me show you how to do that so if we
go up to the very top here and we put an
asterisk this is basically saying
so every element every style and we will
set this to margin:0 padding:0 and
that'll that'll zero everything out
that's called a reset okay so if we
reload now the h1 and the paragraph
you'll see they don't have any margin or
padding by default so you may want to
add a reset if you want to just zero
everything out and go from there without
any confusion of having you know initial
padding and margin on certain elements
so it's completely up to you if you want
to do that but I'm actually just going
to comment this out so it doesn't take
effect all right so we have some padding
on the top but what I want to do is add
padding all around so what I could do is
we could do it the long way
so we could say bottom right left okay
we could do that but you don't want to
do that especially if it's going to be
20 pixels or no matter what size on any
side you just want to use padding okay
so we'll say padding 20 pixels and let
me just put a comment here and I'm just
going to say same as above all right now
margin on the other hand is going to be
the space outside of the border all
right so let's say we want to add margin
top and we'll say 20 pixels what that
should do is move the entire thing down
because it's going to add space above it
okay and again we can do this with
margin or we could just say margin 20
pixels and that's going to put it all
the way around okay you'll see that it
actually got skinnier because it added
20 pixels here but let's say we just
wanted the margin on the top and bottom
we could do 20 pixels and then zero for
the right and left all right
reload and there we go all right so now
I want to move on to some text
formatting styles so what I'm going to
do is I'm going to target the box one h1
okay so this is saying that I want to
style any h1 that is within this class
okay it's not going to style any h1
that's not in this class so let's start
with let's just change the font family
okay so we don't have to have one font
family for the whole site let's say we
want to use two Homa reload and I see
that this is now a Houma font
let's say we want to change the font
weight to 800 and let's say we want it
to be italic we could say font style set
that to italic and if we reload there we
go
so if font weight font style we have
text decoration which we could do a
underline if we wanted to okay that
gives it an underline if we wanted to
change it to all uppercase we could use
the text transform and say uppercase ok
reload now it's all uppercase let's see
what else letter spacing so if we want
to put space between the letter this
would usually be with the M unit so
let's say 0.2 m and now reload and now
you see this space between each letter
and then we also have word spacing say
word spacing and we'll say 1 M reload
and you see that now there's more space
between each word so these are just some
text formatting styles alright let's go
ahead and put another box on the page
just to add some more HTML so I'm going
to copy box 1 and we'll change this to
box - and that's fine we'll leave the
same text I guess where you load
actually change the heading we'll say
goodbye world
alright now notice that we don't have
any styling because we're now using a
box to class not box 1 if we if we
change this to box 1 of course it's
going to apply those styles
but let's change it to box two and then
in the CSS will just say box two and
let's see I don't want to add a bunch of
crazy styles let's just give it a border
and let's say we want three three pixels
and we'll do dotted and let's do like a
light gray reload okay so now I have a
border let's add padding 20 pixels and
let's say margin let's do 20 pixels top
and bottom zero left and right okay so
to add some padding and also added
margin on the top and bottom so next
thing I'm going to do is let's add let's
out of some a list I tie unordered list
alright so let's go back to our HTML
I'll go under box two and let's put a
div we'll give this will give it a class
of let's say categories and let's put an
h2 will say categories and let's put a
UL with some allies okay each li will
have an a tag which will just go nowhere
I'll say category one I'm just going to
like that we'll see category one two
three and four alright so now we have a
simple list this is what it will look
like by default with no CSS so now let's
go over to our style dot CSS file and
let's apply some styles to categories
remember categories is actually the div
that surrounds this it's not the actual
list itself okay and that's what I mean
with CSS you can do you can do the same
thing a million different ways we could
have put the class on the actual UL but
you know you'll find your your way of
doing things so it's just give it a
border of one pixel one pixel like gray
solid
and then we'll just give it a give some
padding of 10 pixels all the way around
okay it's going to just go around the
whole thing there's also a border-radius
property that we could use and that's
that can give it rounded corners so
let's say 15 pixels and reload and now
notice that this box has curved edges
all right oh let's see what else
text a line so that's something you
might use a lot so let's say categories
are categories and I think it was within
an h1 we gave it an h2 so let's say we
want the h2 to be aligned to the center
so we'll say text-align:center reload
and now you'll see it's in the middle
all right let's apply some styles to the
UL and the end the Li tags so we'll say
categories UL now ul is by default have
some padding you see they pushed over I
think it's like 40 pixels so let's
actually zero that out by saying
padding:0 okay if we reload and you'll
see that it gets rid of that you can
also change the bullet points if you
want by using list style
so if we say list style square and
reload now there's still squares you can
also completely get rid of them by
saying list-style:none okay reload and
now it doesn't have any all right now
before we get to the styling the Li tags
let's talk a little bit about links
because links actually have different
states now I could say categories a -
just just target the links in that in
the categories but I'm actually going to
go up top here and apply a global styles
to the link so just a so this will apply
to any link on the page so let's start
by getting rid of the underlined so
we'll say text-decoration:none okay
that's going to get rid of that annoying
underlined and you probably want to
change the color because the default
blue is really ugly so let's change it
to black
okay so now you can see the links are
black now as I said they have different
states so they have a hover State so we
can say a : hover and let's say we want
to change the color to red when they're
hovered so reload now when I hover over
each link it turns red there's also an
active State and active make it green
active is just when you click on it it
just flashes real quick you see how it
turns green for a second when I click on
it that that's meaning it's active all
right we also have a visited state so if
we say a visited and let's say color
yellow okay now if I reload they're all
going to turn yellow because we did
visit all of these but if we were to add
another one say category five and save
reload
I guess that's oh you know what let's
let's make a go somewhere else will say
test HTML okay so now it's black because
it goes by the actual location but if I
click on that obviously that goes
nowhere because it's a blank page but if
we go back and reload well I guess it
doesn't work because it's not an actual
page hmm so I guess I mean if we created
a test dot HTML that that should turn
yellow I honestly haven't can't remember
the last time I use visited but just so
you guys know you can do that alright so
let's go back down to our categories and
let's let's get rid of that style
actually I don't want the visited to be
yellow so let's make it black all right
so now let's say categories allies and
for the Li let's add a little bit of
padding to the bottom so we'll say 8
pixels and let's actually add a border
to the bottom
we'll say dotted one pixel and we say
three three three four the color will
reload and now it looks something like
that
alright let's actually do not heat
pixels we'll do six all right now for
the bullet points you can do this list
style you can do it on either the UL or
the Li and then we also have this list
style image okay and you can actually
set this to an image like you would set
a background image which I'll get into
later so let's say URL and we'll say
slash images slash check dot PNG alright
and what I'm going to do is grab an
image let's say checkmark images and
let's grab this check mark right here
and we're just going to save it as check
PNG and we're going to save it in our
desktop CSS crash course CSS cheat sheet
and I'm going to create a folder called
images okay and then in there we'll save
it and then let's go to our site and
reload and notice that it uses the
actual size of the image so I'm going to
make that smaller okay and you can do
that however you want I'm just going to
open it with Photoshop let's see is this
the right folder desktop alright so I'm
just going to open this real quick and
you like I said you can resize it
however you want I'm just giving you an
example of what I do to resize images so
I'm just going to go to the image size
change it to 10 pixels and then I'm just
going to resave it as a PNG file save so
now so now it should be 10 pixels so
let's reload and now you can see we have
the little checks next to our categories
alright and you may want to push this
over a little bit if you're going to use
bullet points because we set the padding
to zero
let's say we just want to say
padding-left
20 pixels and that'll push it over all
right guys so we're starting to run out
of time I still want to get to the
layout page so this may be a little
longer than an hour but let's move on to
forms okay because forms are very ugly
by default and we want to stay within
the container which ends right here I'm
actually going to put a comment here
oops just letting us know that this is
where the container ends because we want
to stay within it all right so let's go
ahead and put in a form and I'm actually
going to just paste all the fields in I
just make this bigger so basically what
I did just tab this back basically what
I did is I created a couple fields and I
wrapped them in a div with the class of
form group okay if you've used bootstrap
before this is actually the class they
use and then we have the label and we
have the input so we have a name email
and then a text area which is a message
and then a simple submit button all
right so let's save that see what it
looks like by default okay so it looks
pretty damn ugly now you know I don't
want you guys to have to look at the
very bottom of the screen so let me just
really quickly I'm going to put a div in
here and just give it an inline style of
margin top 500 pixels just to push
everything down or push everything up
all right so let's go ahead and start to
make this form look a little better so
we're going to go to our style CSS
actually let's give the form a class so
we'll say class my form alright and then
in here we're going to target my form
and first of all I'm just going to add
some padding we'll see 20 pixels that'll
be around the entire form okay and then
let's let's separate the the form group
a little bit each field so remember we
gave it a class of form group
so we're just going to add some padding
bottom of 15 pixels and I'll separate it
a little bit now for the label labels
are in line that's why they're on the
same level same level of the input gay
inputs and labels are in line I want
this to be on a separate line without
having to put an actual line break in so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to set
the label actually know what we should
be putting my form before all of these
like that I will say my form label and
then I'm going to display that even
though it's in line we can set it to be
a block okay and remember block level
elements they'll they'll put it on a new
line and they go across the entire
blinds so if we save now you see that
labels are on their own line now let's
make these text inputs look a little
better so we'll say my form input and
let's add some padding to make them look
a little thicker so we'll say 8 pixels
and then let's also set the width to be
a hundred percent of its container so
reload now a couple things here notice
that since we said just input that's
going to pertain to any input even the
button which is also an input if we had
let's say a radio button it would
pertain to that as well and it didn't
target this because this is actually a
text area it's not an input tag now what
we could do is we can target certain
types of inputs so these are both texts
right so what we can do is put a set of
brackets here and we can say type equals
text and then what that's going to do
when I reload it should disregard the
button because that's not the type of
text okay see what I'm saying
and then the text area we also want to
add those styles too so I'm just going
to put a comma here and we're just going
to say dot my form text area where you
load and then it applies it to that as
well
now let's add a little bit of styling to
the button here so what I could do is I
could say my form input and then we
could say lips like it's a type equals
submit okay we can do that and let's
give it a background color of dark gray
we'll make the color white let's say
padding on the top and bottom will do 15
now we'll do 10 pixels and left and
right 15 and then let's say border none'
okay let's reload and now we get this
button now this is fine but what I what
I want to do is I want to have a class
called button that we can apply to any
button and get this style so instead of
doing this right here what I'm going to
do is just change this to dot button and
since this is just global not part of
just the form I'm going to just put it
up here instead so let's go like under
the container and then what I would do
is apply that class to this input okay
well actually I already did
I already did do it so that should still
work all right now if I wanted to put a
button somewhere else like let's say in
box 2 or not even just a button it could
be a link so we'll just put a link we'll
say read more if we just leave it like
that of course it's going to just look
like that but if we put class button now
we get that okay and actually sent it to
link we want that color to be white so
let's go back to button let's see color
you know what it's getting this is
mixing it up the visited color so let's
just let's actually get rid of that
right there
there we go all right cool so we can
apply that class anywhere and if we
wanted to put a hover State for the
button we could do that as well so if we
say button hover and let's say
background red color white and now we
have that color that hover effect all
right hopefully that isn't too confusing
so that's our form very simple now what
I want to do is talk about alignment and
floating okay so let's go back to our
HTML we'll go under the form and what
I'm going to do here is I'm going to put
in three blocks okay so it's a give and
let's give this a class of block and
inside these blocks will have an h3 will
just say heading and then we'll have a
paragraph with some dummy text I'm just
going to make it a little shorter let's
go like right there look and we're going
to have three of these so let's copy
this whole div with the class of block
paste it in two more times and reload so
normal flow we're just going to have
them on top of each other but let's say
we wanted to float them to go to the
side all right we want them to go
horizontally so let's go to our CSS
remember they all have a class of block
so we're going to say we want these to
float to the raw exits they float left
and we're going to set a width now since
there's three of them I'm going to set
the width to 33.3%
all right and then let's just add like
actually let's just do that for now
let's see what that does
alright so reload and now we have our
three blocks now if I wanted to let's
say put a border we'll say one pixel
solid C and let's put in padding 10
pixels and let's reload now that's going
to mess everything up because what it's
doing is it's taking this width which
which just barely fits everything in and
then it's adding 10 pixels padding it's
adding a pixel of border which makes it
too big to put all on the same line so
the easy fix for this is to add a
property called box sizing whoops not
box shadow box sizing and we set this to
the value of border box so if we save
that and reload now notice we they're
all back on the same line because what
this does is it makes it so that it
takes in padding and border and it takes
this stuff in and applies it into the
width itself so that it's not adding it
to it making it too big or too wide
alright so just to let you know now when
you get into flex box flex box takes
care of this stuff really nicely and you
can do a lot more but like I said that's
too advanced for this video for this
tutorial you might want to check out the
flex box in 20 minutes video that I did
alright so what about floating elements
that aren't all the same width like this
let's go ahead and do like like a main
area and a sidebar so we'll go below
those three blocks now when you float
stuff you're going to want to clear it
because that your next your next mark up
is going to be all messed up it's going
to be like up here so what we do is we
create a div let's give it a class of
CLR you might also see clear fix
sometimes I like to use CLR and then I'm
going to put this at the top because
this is kind of a global class so we'll
go like right here and say dot CLR and
we just want to add clear folks and
that's going to clear any floats above
it okay
and then what we'll do is create a give
this time I'm going to give it an ID so
I'll give it an idea of main block all
right and then let's also do a div with
an ID of sidebar okay so in the main
block let's just grab this h3 in this
paragraph and then sidebar we'll just
just have the paragraph so by default
obviously these are going to be on top
of each other but let's say we want the
heading to be kind of the main area and
take up like this much space and then
the sidebar over here so what we would
do is go to our CSS and remember their
ID so we want to use a number sign and
let's say main block
okay main block and we're going to float
that to the left and then I'm going to
set a width of 70% okay because I want
this to be kind of responsive all right
and then let's copy that and then for
this will say sidebar that's what I
called it right sidebar and we want that
to flow to the right and we want that to
be 30% all right so let's go ahead and
save that reload and there we go now for
the sidebar I'm also going to add
actually add a background color of dark
gray color white oops color white and
let's add padding 15 pixels and save
okay now again it's not it's going to go
on down here doesn't look right so what
we need to do is just add in our border
I'm sorry our box-sizing of border box
okay and we're going to also add some
padding in the border box on our main
block okay so now we'll reload and there
we go so now it's it's loaded correctly
all right so we are getting there guys
now I want to talk a little bit about
positioning all right so the position
property has a few different values so
static is actually the default if we
don't assign a position its static this
just renders the elements in order of
the document flow relative means that
the element is positioned relative to
its normal position so it falls
naturally but we can add that we can add
properties like top left right bottom
and so on and we can push it to where we
want now absolute will allow us to
target whatever position we want inside
of a relative element and I'll show you
what I mean in a second fixed is a fixed
position to the browser window so no
matter how is how much we scroll where
we are on the page it'll always be in
the same position initial sets the
property to its default value and then
inherit will inherit whatever the
property of its parent element so let's
take a look at some of these in action
all right guys so back to our HTML
remember we did float the main block in
sidebar so I'm going to go under those
two divs and just clear it out so we'll
say div and we're going to give it a
class of CLR okay and then what I'm
going to do is I'm going to create a div
and let's give this a class of P - box
for positioning box alright and then I'm
going to put an h1 in here we'll just
say hello and then let's also put an h2
and we'll say goodbye and I'm just using
these so I can give you some examples on
positioning so let's go ahead and save
that now if we reload we're just going
to see the two headings but we're going
to go to our CSS now just that a little
smaller and let's see we're going to
target the P - box element that we just
created and I'm going to set a specific
width and height to this so let's say
800 pixels for the width height we'll
say 500 pixels and then let's just add a
border around it so we can definitely
see it so one pixel solid one pixel
solid black
all right so if we look at that that's
what it's going to look like now let's
add a little margin to the top to push
it down a little bit all right so this
is position static by default now I want
these to be positioned absolute so I can
move them around wherever I want within
its element now to do that actually let
me show you let me show you what happens
if we don't set it to relative first
so if we say dot P box and let's target
the h1 that should be a dot all right
and then let's say top and we'll set it
to 40 pixels so let's see what happens
when I reload to this h1 nothing let's
see that's because I didn't set it to
absolutely
I want position position absolute all
right and then reload and now it
disappears now it doesn't actually
disappear what happens is if we go up
here here it is so what's going on is
it's we're saying top 40 pixels so it's
coming down 40 pixels from the top now
since it doesn't have a apparent element
that is positioned relative it's just
going to use the entire HTML document
okay as its container now we want it to
be pushed 40 pixels from the top of this
element of P box so in order for that to
happen we need to actually set this to
position relative all right so now if we
save and reload now it's pushed 40
pixels from the top and just to show you
I'll change it to a hundred all right
and then we can basically put this
element wherever we want if we want it
to go let's say from the left 200 pixels
reload and then you can see it's down
100 and to the left or to the right from
the left 200 okay let's say we wanted to
move goodbye like somewhere down here
we'll say
P - box and will target target the H -
set it to position:absolute and then
let's say we want it from the bottom 40
pixels and then let's say from the right
100 pixels
okay reload and there we go so you can
see we can put this stuff wherever we
want this is really helpful when you're
building games that have to do with CSS
all right you can imagine moving like a
little image a little checker or
something around the board all right now
let's let's look at fixed positioning
real quick so what I'll do is I'm going
to actually go outside of the container
and I'm going to create an a tag
alright let's actually give it a class
of button okay I remember we have that
button class and I'm also going to give
it a class of I would say fix me okay so
it has two classes now fix me and button
now if I reload it's going to show down
in here
whoops we have no text inside the link
we'll just say hello all right so we
have this button hello now - if we set
it to fixed what it'll do is it'll be
kind of stuck on the page somewhere and
how wherever we scroll it'll still stay
there so let me show you we go down here
we say dot fixed me and then we're going
to set position to fixed and then let's
set top - 400 pixels all right so now if
we save and reload you'll see that that
button is now going to stay there 400
pixels from the top of the browser and
it sits it's not going to move okay no
matter where we are on the web page and
that's really cool for like like social
media links things like that where you
want you know you want the user to
always see it sometimes you'll even see
this with the nav bar so when you scroll
down the nav bar still shows all right
so we're past an hour now and we still
have to do the layout so I apologize
that this is taking so long but I do
want to cover our
so what I want to do now is show you how
to use an image as an element background
so we're going to use this right here
this P box so let's see I'm just going
to grab an image real quick say light
abstract image actually that's not what
I want
let's grab this right here alright so
I'm going to grab this image and I'm
going to just save it as BG image dot
jpg and we'll save it to our cheat sheet
images folder all right and then let's
go back and close those let's go back to
our CSS and under P box let's say
background - image and then that's going
to say URL and then in here we need a
path a path to the image so it's going
to be dot dot slash because right now
we're in the CSS folder but we want to
go outside of it so that brings us out
and then we want to go into the images
folder and then we want to call BG image
dot jpg all right so let's save that and
reload and now you'll see we have the
image as the background now there's
there's different there's different
background styles we can use so for
instance the position so let's go down
here and say background position and
we're going to set that to let's say a
hundred pixels 200 pixels and reload
what that's going to do is it's going to
push it down 100 pixels and push it or
push it over a hundred pixels and down
200 now notice that it's actually
repeating the image is repeating okay
this is the end and then it repeats both
ways so what we're going to do is set
background - your repeat to no-repeat
all right and reload and now you'll see
that it does not repeat now for a
background position
you can also use I cannot type position
today you can also use Center let's say
Center Center and reload and that will
Center it on the you know horizontally
and vertically we could say Center top
reload and that will Center at top so
you can use pixels or you can use Center
you can also use percentages I believe
alright but that's what work that's all
we're going to do with the background
images alright so the last thing I want
to do inside the cheat sheet is I want
to I want to show you a little bit about
pseudo classes so what I'm going to do
is in the container under the P Box
let's go ahead and put in a UL we're
going to have a bunch of allies I'm just
going to stay list item and we'll copy
that I'm just going to have a bunch of
these ok so will reloads with a bunch of
list items and we can use pseudo classes
to target certain things so let's say
that let's give that a class actually
so UL class we'll just call it my list
alright so we'll say dot my list and
actually we're going to target an Li and
then I'm going to use a pseudo class by
using a colon and we're going to say
first - child
ok and then we're going to set the
background will say background and we'll
set that to red notice that we don't
have to use background - color we can
use background and then we can use
either a color or an image here okay and
that's going to get the first child it's
going to get the first Li we also have
last child
okay so last child and we'll change that
to let's say blue I'm not going to go
over all the pseudo elements but just
some of the important ones now let's say
you wanted to target like the fifth one
of this so what you could do and this is
all css3
we can say my list Li and then we can
use something called nth and child and
then it's we're going to put in some
parentheses here and let's say we want
the fifth so we could put five and then
we'll stay color or let's say background
yellow
all right so we'll reload and now the
fifth one is yellow so you can target
whatever one you want using these pseudo
elements now you can also use even an
odd with nth child so let's copy that
and let's say we want all of the even to
be gray and reload and now all the even
list items will have a gray background
so very very helpful especially if the
stuff is dynamically generated and you
can't really target a specific list item
alright guys so we've looked at quite a
bit pretty much all the the fundamentals
of CSS as far as the the properties and
all that I mean there are more but it's
impossible to go over all of them in
this amount of time
I'm way over what I wanted to do but I
do want to do what I promised and kind
of create a website layout for you guys
so hopefully this isn't too long if
you've watched it up to this point then
I'm sure you won't mind watching another
you know 10-15 minutes so I'm going to
do this kind of quick because we did go
over you know most of the stuff that
we're going to be doing here so in my
website I'm going to create a new file
called index.html why do I keep doing
that I do that because I usually use
Adam and when you do that you create a
new file you can just type the name and
say if you don't have to do ctrl s
alright and then let's create a folder
called CSS and we'll create another
folder called images all right now in
CSS we'll create a file and let's save
it as style dot CSS okay we're now in
the my website folder cheat sheet is
done okay so we have these two files
let's go ahead and add some basic markup
to our website let's just say my web
site all right and then we want to link
the style sheet so it's linked to CSS
slash style dot CSS and then we're going
to write our markup and that's usually
what I like to do is do the markup first
and then the styling so we're going to
be using html5 html5 semantic elements
so let's start with a header and our
header is just going to basically have
an h1 and we'll just call it my website
that's kind of like our logo and I'm
going to give this header an ID of main
header all right now we're going to have
a container class that's going to push
everything to the middle and so on but I
don't want to wrap it around the whole
site because I don't want everything to
be pushed over for instance the header I
want the background color to go across
the whole thing but I want the content
the actual h1 to be you know to have the
container around it so we're going to be
using the container inside of this and
inside a lot of our elements alright so
there's our header next thing we'll do
is the navbar and again we're going to
have the container inside of it so what
I'm going to do is just copy this we'll
change this to nav change the ID to
navbar make sure you change that as well
and then we're going to have our UL
let's do our L eyes okay our a tags I'm
not going to actually go anywhere but
this is our fake navigation so we'll say
home about services and contact all
right and then under that we're going to
have like a showcase area so for that
I'm going to use a section tag and I'm
going to give this an ID of showcase
notice these are these are the things
that you use IDs for because I'm not
going to have another main nav bar or
another main header or showcase the
is all unique stuff so I'm giving it an
ID okay so that that gives you an
example of the difference all right
and then container however we're using
in all different places so that is a
class okay let's put an h1 in our
showcase just put some dummy text I want
it really short though so I'll just do
that all right so that's our showcase
two tab that over and then under the
showcase we're going to have like the
main area which is also going to be a
section so let's say section say section
ID main and we'll just put an h1 in here
we'll say welcome and then we'll have a
paragraph with some dummy text now the
main area will be on the left and then
you'll have a sidebar which is going to
be an aside all right and the aside I'm
going to give that an ID as well of
sidebar all right and then let's see
what I want to put here let's just let's
we'll just put some text just copy this
I'll make it a little shorter though all
right now the main and the sideb I do
want both of those push to the middle so
I'm going to wrap a container around
both of those and once this comes
together you'll see exactly why I'm
doing this oops
all right and then finally we just want
a footer so we're going to use an html5
split our tag and let's give that an ID
of main footer
okay we'll put a paragraph and would say
copyright ampersand 2017 my website
alright so that should be all the
mock-ups so now let's go to our file
path here it's in crash course slash
actually we'll just open it from from
explorer see my website index.html so
that's what it looks like without CSS
why isn't that oh my god that should be
copy 2017 all right so this is what it
looks like without CSS now we're going
to start to add our Styles again I'm
going to be doing this kind of quick
because a lot of this stuff we already
went over so let's say body it's a
background or background color like grey
a lot of the styles would be the same as
well so say color will be five font
family font family arial helvetica
sans-serif okay we'll set the font size
to 16 let's set the line height and
these are just common settings that I
use a lot for line height and so on and
then I'm going to just margin out to
zero alright and then the container so
container will be 80% and want the
margin auto and we're going to set
overflow to hidden so that there's no
scroll bars even if something goes
outside of its container all right now
remember we have the header which has an
ID of main header so for that I'm going
to set the background X let's do
background color and I'm going to set
that to the color coral and then set the
actual text color to white
all right so let's look at that that's
what it looks like now we want to style
the navbar and this is um this is
actually really easy all we need to do
is take the padding away from the UL
take the the bullet points away
we need to float the links or not float
but display them in line okay so that
you know they float across well I guess
we will fold them as well I'm sorry
we're not going to make the links in
line we're going to make the list items
in line so let's grab the UL so we'll
say main I'm sorry navbar let's do the
navbar itself first excuse me which is
going to have a background color of dark
gray we'll say color white and let's say
okay that's fine we'll just leave that
and then the navbar ul let's let's get
rid of the padding let's get rid of
these bullet points so let's style none
all right so if we go ahead and we look
at it that's what it'll look like
now the Li tags we want those to be in
line instead of block so let's say
navbar navbar Li and we're going to set
display:inline all right now if we look
at that you'll see now that they go to
the side and then the last part of the
navbar to style is the links so now bar
a let's set the color to white let's set
the text decoration to none let's set
the color to well we already did the
color let's set the font size to 18
pixels make them a little bigger and
then padding right so we don't want them
so close together to 15 pixels reload
and there we go there's our navbar
so next thing is the showcase so
showcase and we're going at we're going
to set a background image for this oops
I'll just type it background image URL
okay that's going to be we go dot dot
slash images slash showcase dot jpg so
let's get that image that was the light
abstract coral where is it narrow this
down to large this is that it I don't
think that's it right here I'm going to
grab this image here and you can use
whatever image you want but I'm going to
save this make sure it's in the my
website images and we're going to call
this showcase alright so if we go back
to our site actually we need to add some
other stuff here so we have the
background image let's set the position
so background position I'm going to set
that to center right and let's set the
height now I'm going to set it just as
height for now but then I'm going to
show you something alright and then
let's uh that's good let's save it all
right
so for actually let's add a couple other
things here will stay margin-bottom
because you want to push everything down
let's say 30 pixels everything under the
showcase and then let's also text the
line to the center ok now I want to grab
on to the h1 that's in the showcase so
for the h1 I'm going to change the color
to white I'm going to change the font
size to 50 I want to make it bigger I'm
going to change the line height I'm
going to change that to 1.6 m and then
just add some padding to the top 30
pixels so that'll move the h1 down so
let's go ahead and reload all right now
as I go smaller here notice that the
text goes outside of the of the height
here so this is a case where you want to
use min height okay because you want the
height to gradually grow if the text
grows so in the showcase instead of just
height we're going to say min - height
so if we're at this level there we go
300 but if we make it smaller you'll see
that it'll let the height will grow with
the text which is what we want that
makes it responsive in fact this website
will be responsive all right so that's
the showcase now for the main and the
sidebar so we have the main part here
right and then this is the sidebar we
want them want to float those so let's
say main flow to the left set the width
to 70% padding set to 0 30 pixels and
then let's set the box sizing to border
box so it includes that padding and
stuff all right and then for the sidebar
I'm going to be kind of similar so I'm
going to just copy that I'll say sidebar
it's going to float to the right
we're going to give it a width of 30
let's give it a background background of
oops dark gray and a color of white and
that should be good actually to do
padding 10 pixels all the way around
reload there we go and then for the
footer remember it has an idea of main
footer I'm going to set background of
dark gray color of white oops
text a line to the center and what else
padding through 20 pixels of padding and
then let's move it down a little so
margin top say 40 pixels save that
reload and there's our footer now the
last step is to make it completely
responsive right now if we go down small
like this I don't want these to be
floated so what we need to do is add a
media query we can add a media query by
saying add media and then the condition
is if it's a max width of 600 pixels so
anything we any styles we put in here
are only going to be in effect if it's
under 600 pixels like this over here and
what we want to do is we want to remove
the floats from the main and the sidebar
we also want to change the width to a
hundred percent okay for both of those
so let's say named with a hundred
percent and then we want to say float
none
okay same thing with the sidebar so
basically they just go on top of each
other all right so let's save reload and
there we go so we now have a responsive
website using CSS alright so that was a
long video guys hopefully learned a lot
I feel like it was it was pretty good it
was conveyed pretty well you know let me
know if you think different or let me
know if you liked it please subscribe if
you liked it
and that's it thanks for watching guys I
do have a patreon account that's linked
in the description if you guys want to
support me even further even for a
dollar per month I do have a couple
perks and I'm come in the process of
figuring out some more to give to my
patrons so check that out it's in the
description and thanks for watching guys
see you next time