all right Hoss says listen up in this
video we got to learn about the word
continued now I actually told you guys
that I was going to teach us in the last
video but then I got rambling on about
comments and probably something else
stupid so we'll go ahead and learn about
continue in this tutorial so what I want
to do is I want to make a list a real
quick and I'm going to name it numbers
taken and of course I always like to
pretend like I'm the coach of a hockey
team that's like my little arm dream in
life I'm the coach of the hockey team
coaching Team USA and we beat Russia at
the I don't know like 20,000 something
Olympics so anyways that's my dream
let's get back to real-life tutorials so
all of these numbers resemble people on
my team their jersey number so of course
what I want to do is I want to make a
program to loop through and it pretty
much says what jerseys you are allowed
to have still so we'll make like a list
from 1 to 50 and it will include all of
the numbers except these ones easy
enough so what I can do is a let me give
you guys just a little print statement
here are the numbers that are still
available so all the players who haven't
picked jersey yet can see this program
and pick a number from this list so of
course the first thing we do is put 4 n
in range and I'll just put the numbers 1
250 actually let me change that to 20
it'll be easier to see I'll change this
to like 13 so of course this is going to
loop through the numbers 1 to 19 and
I'll just make a simple if statement so
if n in numbers taken and let me write
this entire programs and then I'll
explain to you guys what it does all
right
so as you can see what's going to happen
is it's going to loop through the
numbers 1 to 20 and it's going to print
all of the numbers except for the ones
in this list right here so 1 it's going
to check of twos in there and if it does
it's going to skip it so that's how you
can kind of think of continued so unlike
break whenever you know that whenever
you have break it breaks out of the loop
completely and stops the entire loop
what continue is going to do it says ok
whenever you get to this word continue
whatever is after this in the loop just
skip it and go to the next iteration of
the loop so if something was after it it
wouldn't break out of the loop
completely and stop the loop it would
keep going
it would just skip what's ever after it
so just just kind of explain a couple of
these loops so the first time N equals 1
so says is 1 in the numbers taken nope
so I'm going to print out one next time
n equals 2 is 2 and the numbers taken
well yes it is so continue what does
that mean it means anything after this
say maybe we had a bunch of lines it
said skip all of these then just go back
to the start of the loop where N equals
the next number in this case 3 oops to
leave the extra line there so again real
simple will continue means is keep going
with the loop but skip anything after it
and break means break out of the loop
completely stop it and continue with the
rest of your code so hopefully you guys
understand and I was actually going to
teach you about functions in this story
but I think we're out of time so well
thank you guys for watching and don't
forget to subscribe and see you later