alright guys so about two weeks ago I
had this big cardboard box to throw away
so I have this trash service that comes
in picks on my trash every week so I
just set it right next to my trash and
they just took my trash but they left
the box so I'm like alright maybe if I
put it inside the trash can
then then they'll do it so last week
that's what I did I ripped it up I put
it in the trash can and then when they
came they this took the one with the
trash and left the cardboard so sorry
sounds like alright it must be like um I
not must not be allowed to throw away
cardboard or something so what I did is
I this week I ripped it up and I stuffed
it inside a bag and then I put the bag
inside my garbage can and this morning
the dude knocks on my door and he goes
sir can you stop trying to throw away
your cardboard please so that was kind
of embarrassing however I think if I
just give up now then it'll be like
admitting defeat so if anyone has any
really interesting arm techniques I can
use to secretly throw away my cardboard
let me know because I'm going to win
this battle mr. trash man so again that
wasn't like an analogy or something
that's just a stupid story nothing to do
with Python so let's go ahead and get
started learning Python okay in this
tutorial I want to talk to you guys
about the if statement now the if
statement is a cool keyword if and it's
a way to have your computer program make
a very simple decision now pretty
interesting pretty unique if I just say
that so let's go ahead and get started
now the cool thing is since we have this
IDE we can make programs longer than
just one line and whenever we hit Enter
of course it doesn't just execute
automatically so say that we wanted to
build a program that takes a user's age
and we'll say that we're like selling
beer online or something even though
that's illegal
we'll do it anyways so if the users age
is above 21 then we'll say um you can
buy beer if not then we'll say okay
you're not allowed buy beer because they
have to be 21 so what we do is we need a
way to
this and execute some code based on
another variable sounds confusing but
check it out so whatever you want to
have your computer make a decision the
first thing you do is add the keyword if
now directly after this we need to give
it something to test so right now we're
just going to test if this age is less
than 21 so if the age is less than 21
then we want to do something we'll just
like print out no beer for you since I
they're too young so right after your
test add a colon now hit enter and you
can see that your cursor doesn't go to
the next line it's automatically
indented in one tab now anything that's
indented in one tab your computer knows
okay only execute this code if this test
is true so this code that we type right
here is only going to run if the users
age is less than 21 so what do we want
to happen if the users age is less than
21 we'll just print no beer for you all
right so this is a valid print statement
and it does indeed print texts out on
the screen
however check it out whenever we run it
nothing's displaying in our console at
the bottom and that's because even
though we wrote this line of code it
didn't execute because the age was over
21 so we didn't need to give them this
little warning now if we have some
little kid who's like 13 try to use the
site it's going to say okay if 13 is
less than 21 that's true 13 is indeed
less than 21 then that's when we want to
print this no beer for you so whenever
you run this it says okay check this and
okay that is true so run this line of
code so again whenever the test is true
run it whenever it's false just move on
so it executes what's ever down here now
what if we wanted to have the computer
side between one of two things because
of course whenever the user is less than
we gave me the warrant a message but
what about for the people who are older
than 21
how do we make them you know use the
site or something like that well we can
add another condition called e.l.f and
this checks something else and they'll
probably be easier to see if I use a new
example so let's make a new variable
called name hey take it easy caps log
name and we'll set this equal to Lucy
so let's some check if we'll say we'll
check if their name is Bucky or Lucy how
do we do that well we already know how
to check if name now I'll tell you guys
about another type of test so with
numbers we can do less than greater than
however since this is a string we want
to see if it's equal to something else
so the key word for this is is so this
is pretty much going to check this name
and see if it's equal to something else
and of course Eddie or : so again less
than greater than four numbers and with
strings you can use this keyword is you
can actually use is when comparing two
numbers as well so what we're going to
do is say okay if the name is Bucky then
print arm a there Bucky
now in order to test another option what
you can use is the keyword
al if' and this pretty much means else
if or it's just another way of having
another if statement in one block of
code so else if the name is Lucy prints
what are we going to print for Lucy
something get a like what up loose dog
all right so okay i think thats ghetto
enough so pretty much it checks the name
if it's Bucky print this statement to
them if it's Lucy print this statement
to him and we can actually have as many
of these el ifs if we want so we'll say
okay if it's Sammy be like what up
Slammy so pretty much it's going to go
one by one and only execute a certain
block of code whenever the condition is
true
so hit run and of course the name is
Lucy so said what up loose thought so
pretty much it ran through top to bottom
and said okay
is this true nope so go down here is
this true yes so do this and of course
since this was not true it skipped this
one as well okay simple enough so now we
have a way where we not only can make a
decision like in that beer example well
we can also make a decision to decide
between more than one option now there's
one other thing I want to talk to you
guys about and that is well what if we
ran through all the options and none of
them were true but we still want to
execute a certain bit of code well we
can do something like this after all of
your el ifs you can have one last
condition called else what else means is
if you ran through every other option
and none of those were true then do this
one so we can just run something like
prints will say that this is actually a
site and if the user logs in then we can
give them a custom message and of course
if none of these names are true then
that just mean they didn't sign up for
the site yet so arm they sign up for the
site so of course with Lucy whenever you
run it it's going to give her that
custom welcome message however if we
have a new new guy name like Tommy Dee
what it's going to do is say are you
this user no check if you're this easier
nope
check in view of this user and since all
of these options are false whenever
you're on this it's going to say please
sign up for the site alright so I know
that was a lot to take in but that is
pretty much how you can have your
computer make one decision multiple
decisions or multiple decisions with a
default answer so I'm going to go
scratch my head and think about how I
can trick my garbage man and again if
you have any questions or you want the
source code to this I'm going to be
posting it on my forum so I'll see you
later