alright guys in this video I'm going to
be talking about keyword arguments in
also explaining all the cool things that
we can do with them so in the last video
all right yeah I don't even know if it
was the last video in one of the past
videos I already showed you guys that
you can have default arguments for
example you can have a number instead
equal to a value or I think we did this
sex and we set it equal to unknown so we
did something like this let me make a
really simple function I'll just name a
dumb sentence and it's going to print
out really dumb sentence and we'll give
it a couple default values and we
already know what those are so I will
explain them again so we'll have a
variable called name have another one
called action and all these are just
going to be a simple string variables
and item so the only purpose of this
function is that print out a dumb
sentence and by default we'll just say
Bucky a tuna using three different
variables so in order to do this print
name action item so right now if I just
run this of course well got phlegm in my
throat so remember when we don't pass in
any arguments it just uses the default I
say the fart default argument so that's
what what is happening right now however
and this is Horo
I want to show you something else so we
have a different couple options of
exactly what parameters we pass in and
how we pass them in so by default
whenever we pass in parameters it's
going to accept them in the order we
pass them in so Sally um what did Sally
do Sally
farts and for the item will just say
Sally farts gently so Sally farts gently
so again this function the function that
we just created it takes three
the string variables now we're passing
in three string variables right now so
what it does is it says okay since you
did this one first this one second in
this one third I'm going to go ahead and
assume that the first one is supposed to
be equal to name the second one action
in the third one item okay makes sense
and that's how we'll display that
whenever or that's how it use this I
should probably say however they're
going to come certain times where maybe
we only want to pass in the second one
or maybe we want to pass in the third
one in the first one so whenever we want
to pass in a limited number of arguments
or we want to pass them in in a
different order this is how we do it we
need to utilize the key word of this
argument right here so say that we
wanted to set the item equal to
something different well if we just
write a string there it's going to think
it's meant for the first one so what we
can do is we can actually type item and
set it equal to awesome so now whenever
you print this out it says Bucky eight
awesome what that doesn't really make
sense so let's go ahead and change that
so in this last example we'll say okay
tree item is awesome instead of tuna and
also for the action it'll make more
sense if we wrote is so again not only
are we choosing the pass in only a
limited number of these parameters just
a second and third one but we can also
pesum it in any order we want pretty
easy especially when ever we wrote a bit
of code and we're giving this to someone
else and allow them to use our functions
so run this and it says Bucky is awesome
so again that is what a keyword argument
is a really cool way to work with
arguments the fasten a limited amount of
arguments or pessimal
any order you want so then guys for
watching and I'll see you later