okay guys in this video I'm gonna talk
to you about modules so sometimes you're
gonna have functions that you're gonna
want to use over and over and over again
maybe not only in the same program but
maybe in different programs so instead
of having to rewrite the function every
single time what you can do is you can
throw all the functions that you're
gonna use over and over again in a
separate file and then just include that
file in whatever program you're working
on so not only does it help you from
writing a bunch of code but it also
helps organize your programming a little
bit better and I'm gonna show you guys
how to make those right now so again
like I said right now we're gonna make a
macho that's just a function included in
another file so we're gonna need another
file so right click on your project and
a write new Python file so I'll just
name this home I don't know like tuna
so tuna dot P Y dot py is the extension
for a Python file and then hit OK so now
our project has two files in the same
directory this main which is our main
program the one we've been working on
and this tuna is the one we just made
and we can just delete that that doesn't
really matter
so in this tuna file I'm just gonna make
a really simple function right now so
death now I'll just call it you can call
it anything you want I'm just name it
fish because I don't know much of his
name to us so why the heck not all right
so this function is just kind of like
prints on my land screen easy colons
alright I'll just say I am a tuna fish
there we go
alright so say that we wanted to use
this function over and over and over
again so we just wrote it once we threw
in a module and we're good to go
so now whenever we actually want to use
it go back to your main program and what
you can do is in order to use any of the
stuff in your module you first need to
say ok we want to include another file
so how do we do that well we actually
type the word import and that means go
get a file from somewhere else in
use it in this program so then it says
okay well what's the name of your file
well it's just called tuna and you don't
write py because whenever you import a
module it knows that of course it's
another Python Python file so again no
need to include that py don't do it it
knows so right now in this program we're
working on we included basically this
basically what's going on behind the
scenes is it goes to this file copies it
and paste it right in here even though
you know you don't see it that's kind of
a good example so if you just run this
right now check it out nothing happens
why is that well we included this but we
didn't say to actually use this function
right in here so in order to use
functions that are inside modules we
just can't write fish like this even
though this function is named fish right
here check it out if we run it it says
okay fish is not defined so why can't we
do that well the reason for that is say
we were including a bunch of modules
maybe root um there's some modules that
we wrote maybe some that our friends
wrote maybe some that some random people
on the internet row well maybe each of
those modules each have a function name
fish so whenever we just call it like
this it's not going to know which
function or what function from the
module to use so before we call the
function we need to specify the name of
the module that were using it from so
tuna da fish what this means is go to
tuna the tuna module and from there call
the function named fish so now whenever
you run it check it out it goes to tuna
finds fish and calls this or runs it
whatever you want to call it so that is
how we can build our own module and use
the crap inside it but there are also
ways to use other people's modules and
I'll show you how to do that right now
so one module that you're going to be
using a lot is called a random and this
is just a simple one to generate a
random number another random stuff so if
you write import random actually it just
pops up right there
and answer what you did is it basically
includes a bunch of functions that they
aren't built into the core Python
language but we can just import them
really easily and we can also download
other modules from the internet and use
those as well but this is the one or
excuse me this is one that's included
with PyCharm so whenever we import it we
can use those functions and I'll show
you guys a real simple one real quick so
we'll just make a random number from
like 100,000 of course the modules name
is random and a function that is inside
it is called R and range and this just
takes a range of numbers like 1 like I
said to a thousand so now what we did is
we generated or n number one two
thousand stored it in the variable X and
if I just print that out and hopefully
this time it was 236 and who the heck is
texting me right now all right anyways I
gotta go deal with that and actually in
the next video what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna show you guys a real cool way in
easy way where you can go grab modules
from the internet and download them and
the cool thing about it is we don't have
to open up our browser or anything all
the tools are built right into PyCharm
so that's what you have to look forward
to I'll see you then