alright guys so the last main concept I
want to talk about regarding arguments
is how to unpack arguments and this is
actually handy and a lot of instances as
you're going to see whenever you make
bigger programs later on so let's go
ahead and make a simple function and
I'll name it health calculator so what
this function does is it takes three
parameters it takes your age we'll say
the amount of apples you ate in a week
and also the amount of cigarettes you
smoke in a week and with this it
calculates on your expected age that
you're going to live - so the formula
for that see if I can come up with
something somewhat realistic is 100
minus your age and then it adds let me
add something they'll be easier
so what Apple is eight and we'll
multiply it by like 3.5 if the values
really weird I can change it later on
but and of course six smoked x - all
right so of course the younger the
better the more apples you a increases
it and the amount of cigarettes you
smoke decreases it so then we get a
final answer and we'll actually say this
isn't your expected age would just say
that this is just some like health
rating on a scale of 1 - yeah like 200
it's probably going to be around so what
we can do of course passing three
parameters here which are three integers
and we can pass them in in a couple
different ways so say that we had a list
and we'll say I don't smoke it also zero
so I'm 27 years old
I eat 20 apples a week I really don't
bug and I actually never smoked a
cigarette in my life because if you do
you are an idiot so this is my
information and we also have information
from a ton of other people because you
know we just came up with this new
formula everyone wants to try it out so
you got a whole database of information
so what we can do is you can run our
program and pass in these parameters the
first way that we knew how the old way
lucky that is zero which is my age lucky
that a 1 which is apples and Buckey data
2 which is cigarette smoke and whenever
you run this all right so my health
rating whatever you know this weird
formula is called is 143 I can guess and
that's pretty good however if we have to
do this for everyone it's going to take
a lot of lines of code so I want to show
you guys a real quick or quicker way so
whenever we call this function what we
can do is we can just actually type the
name of the list right in here and add a
star before it now what this is going to
do is it's called unpacking an argument
list so it pretty much takes this list
and it passes each item in one at a time
so instead of having to write all this
crap we just say okay take this a list
and the extra comedians unpack it so now
whenever you run it check it out it
prints out the same exact thing it
treats it the same exact way it just
saves us a lot of coding so that my
friend is how you unpack arguments and
the good news is right now we're done
with functions we're done with arguments
we're ready to move on to something else
because I want to run through the basics
real quick because I want to start
building bigger awesome programs that
are actually useful so for now of course
thank you guys for watching if you have
any questions asked me on my forum
and I'll see you next time