alright guys so it is 12:35 a.m. and I
actually just got back from Walmart
because I needed groceries and pretty
much the only place that's open around
here like midnight is Walmart so I was
shopping and I was like halfway done
with my shopping actually not even
halfway done and I saw this guy I was
bited like the cheese's I was getting
string cheese and this guy was like
staring at me and I was like huh okay
maybe like knows me from somewhere since
I don't know like high school or
something and so finally after like
staring I prefer minute he like comes up
to me and he's like are you the new
Boston I was like uh yeah and it's
always weird when like people come up to
me because I guess uh like quite a few
people watch my tutorials but it never
shows my face so I don't even know how
people know what I look like but anyways
it was kind of weird because I never I
don't know I just never know what to say
and also at the time the only thing I
had in my car was ground beef and toilet
paper so he probably thinks I'm pretty
weird now but anyways on with the
tutorial where we're going to be talking
about sets so what a set is it's I think
pretty much like a collection of items
but it can't have any duplicates like a
list can so I'll show you guys with
grocery since well it's on my mind I
spell that right
hopefully alright so in order to make a
set it's going to look kind of like a
list except you use these curly braces
right here and let me put a couple
things in here so cereal for some reason
my pie charm seems like it's all well
seems like it's lagging a little bit
alright so cereal milk I got some star
crunches - I'm addicted to those things
however when it's really hot out outside
if you ever eat a star crunch they taste
disgusting which is really weird
alright so so we got some beer or we
have to get beer or whatever this
grocery list is for um duct tape what
else
on my list lotion and what I'm going to
do is I'm going to add beer again now
remember that I told you that what we
did right here is we've made something
called a set that's what this is however
it can't have any duplicates now if you
notice we have beer right here and also
beer right here
twice so what happens is whenever we
print this out print groceries check it
out it prints everything on our list
however it only prints beer once pretty
cool so again this is actually helpful
whenever you make something like a
grocery list or any set where it's
pretty much useless to have the same
item twice so I'll show you guys
simply actually we're making a program
where we're printing out a grocery list
for like I don't know maybe we're making
an app where we can sort grocery lists
online and we can look at it on our
smart phone it's actually a pretty good
idea anyways we'll say if milk and
there's some actually some cool things
that you can do with sets in I can spell
in groceries so this condition right
here it's going to return true if indeed
milk is in groceries which it is right
now so we'll say print um something like
you already have oh no cost so we'll
check pretty much if we're if we already
have the item in there if we do no need
to add it again so else
um prints of like oh yeah you need milk
like a little reminder I don't know
first thing they popped into my head so
of course we run this and it says you
already have milk oz so again that that
is pretty much what set is and that's
one small thing that you can do with a
set you can check if an item is indeed
in
it just like you would a list however in
later tutorials when every are built in
like a little more advanced programs
I'll show you guys some other things
that you can do with sets in how they
are incredibly useful but for now um
thank you guys for watching and I'll see
you later