alright guys welcome to another video
and I'm going to be teaching you about
the for loop in this video pretty much
how we can have a huge list and we can
loop through and pretty much do
something to one item at a time without
having to write code over and over and
over again so you know how in the last
couple of videos I showed you guys how
to make a list with numbers pretty much
you know we did something like that well
in this video I want to spice things up
I'm actually going to be making a list
of foods and of course just like before
whenever we have a list of strings the
set of numbers we put them inside square
brackets and of course we need to put
every string inside a quotation mark
single quotes so we'll say that this is
just my grocery list or something and
the first item is bacon and this is
actually my grocery list believe it or
not so I need to buy tuna running a
little low on that I also need to get
some ham oh was that one other thing I
needed
snausages and I'm having a party um
tomorrow so I got to grab some beef
because it's a beef party so right now
we have a huge list of items of crap
that I got to pick up pretty much for
groceries or just to eat now say that
was making a program to print all of
these items out one by one well okay
print here print oh okay so print oh my
god this is taken forever would it be
awesome
if there is an easy way to loop through
this and write one bit of code to print
each item out one by one
oh well lucky for you guys there is it's
called a for loop now what this does is
it basically takes a list and allows you
to treat each item individually and do
anything you want with it so since these
items are going to change
bacon tuna ham you just can't make five
different variables or else that will
defeat the purpose well I could barely
say that defeat the
best there you go Bucky so pretty much
the first thing you need right after
this for loop is a variable so I'm just
going to name my variable f and this is
going to be a placeholder for each item
so the first time it loops F is going to
be equal to bacon the next time F is
going to be equal to tuna F ham so I
just said F ham like I hate here or
something
but anyways that's what F does and then
we don't need a bunch of variables we
can just use this variable and it's
equal to a bunch of different items
pretty handy so the next thing and the
only other thing you have to write for
the beginning of this loop is what list
do you want to loop through well right
now we only have one list called foods
so foods now if you had um a bunch of
Lists then just make sure to change it
right there but basically arm I mean
this is pretty easy to understand what's
going on it says for F for each item in
foods and the item is going to be named
F that's what our variable is name is
going to be and then what do you want to
do with it well let's just go ahead and
print it out on the screen
first and foremost now let me run this
and you guys are going to see what's
going on so right now we have bacon tuna
ham sausages in beef so what it did
obviously one more time is it looped
through foods and for each item it
treated it as F and with F we could have
done anything we want to it we just
printed it out on the screen simple
enough loops are freakin easy so the
only other thing that I want to talk to
you guys about for now is this you know
in the last couple tutorials I said if
you have a if statement then you put if
test up here and then some code after
and also with a loop make your loop and
then make the code well I want to show
you guys that you're not only limited to
one line of code that you can execute
you can also do something else else for
each item on a new line of code so say
that not only what did we want to print
out the name right here but we also
wanted to print out how many characters
or what so bacon is five tuna is four
ham is
three so on and so forth so let's do
that as well so right under your first
print statement add another print
statement and make sure that this is
indented the same amount if it's right
here it's going to be outside the loop
so make sure it's indented then it'll be
part of the loop now I know I didn't
talk to you guys about this function yet
but whenever you want to print out the
length of something the function name
for that is le n they could have just
wrote lengths but you know no one has
time to write those extra characters so
pretty much that's how you do it and in
the parameters you just have to tell it
what you want to get the length of well
of course F which is going to be the
food so now whenever you run this it
goes through your entire list one item
at a time and then it says for each item
print out the name of that item and then
print out the length of that item so
pretty sweet so again that saved us a
lot of code if we didn't have this loop
then we would have to write two lines of
code for every single item so instead of
ten lines of code we did it in three and
this gets even more useful let's say
you're going through a list of stock
information for last 80 years well you
don't want to you know write however
many thousand lines of code you can just
do it really quick and efficiently now
the only other thing I want to mention
real quick is this you know how in the
last couple stories I showed you guys
how to slice up a list well you can do
the same thing whenever you're looping
so by default when you say for F and
Foods it's going to say okay so you want
me to go through the entire list start
at the beginning
stop at the end well you can also loop
through on a slice of that list by
putting something like this : - now what
this would mean is okay for foods loop
through the items start at the beginning
and stop
at position number two so it's pretty
much just going to do bacon and tuna
right there so again most of the time
whenever you're making loops you're just
going to loop through the entire thing
but I also wanted to tell you guys that
option just in case you ever need to
loop through a certain portion or slice
of the list so I know that was kind of a
lot to take in but pretty simple once
you break it down into pieces and
finally start to understand it so for
now thank you guys for watching we're
going to subscribe and I'll see you guys
in the next video