alright guys welcome back and in this
video I'm going to be teaching you about
strings now a string is just what they
call text in computer programming it's
pretty much like a name a sentence any
of that stuff now whenever you use text
or a string you actually need to include
it in between quotation marks either
double or single if you just try writing
anything like lucky Roberts on the
screen it's going to say invalid syntax
in other words it like thinks it's a
variable or something if you don't
include it in between quotation marks so
if you do that you can type anything you
want and it's good to go again double
quotes or single quotes it doesn't
matter however there are specific times
where you're going to want to use one or
the other
now one of those things is say you have
a sentence like this um alright I'm
going to make a sentence that says I
don't think she's 18
well what these quotes mean is it's
pretty much telling Python where to
begin and where to end so in this
example right up here it started right
here it said Bucky Roberts is awesome
and it ended right here because that's
where your quote is however this
sentence it uses actually one of these
quotes right after the end this
apostrophe right here so Python is going
to think that it starts here stops here
and all the rest of this stuff it's
going to get confused about so whenever
you have a sentence that does use a
single quote what you want to do is you
want to put that in double quotes so I
don't think she's 18 hit enter and it'll
work fine now the opposite of that is
this say that you have a sentence that
you just double quotes like she said
what
part of the cow is the meatloaf rum well
of course this is actually a quote or a
sentence and it uses double quotes so in
this case you would want to surround it
in single quotes easy enough now another
thing that you're going to need to do
sometimes is what if your sentence has
either double quotes and single quotes
in it well you can't just pick one or
the other so what you can do is called
escaping a character I'll show you how
to do that right now so actually let me
see if I can copy this alright so in
this example you see that it thinks it
starts and stops right here however say
that um we have double quotes in here as
well so we need to surround this in
single quotes well what you can do is
whenever it thinks it's the end and you
actually just want to use it as part of
your string right before the quote the
quotation mark you can use a backslash
and whenever you use backslash and then
a symbol after it pretty much means just
treat this is normal text so then it's
going to say okay start here okay
backslash this so that's just normal and
end here boom so again backslash
anything means it's a special meaning
that says treat that as part of the
string now whenever we actually use um
oxygen whenever we print strings out in
our regular program we're not just going
to use the regular text we actually need
to use something called a function and
I'm going to be talking to you about
functions later on but the first
function that we're going to learn is
print it's very easy it's how you print
stuff out on the screen so press print
and that means print stuff out on the
screen and now put two little um
parentheses now in between the
parentheses right any string that you
want so hey now brown cow so this is
actually how we're going to be printing
stuff out on the screen whenever we make
a full piece of software so hit enter
pretty friggin simple now another thing
I should probably mention is this
sometimes you're going to want to I'll
show you an example and I'll show you
guys on the problem it causes and how to
fix it say that we wanted to print out a
path to I don't know some folder on our
desktop so we can do is just okay where
is it see maybe Bucky should move my
cursor out of the way desktop in a you
know my naked pictures of our course in
my nude pics folder so you are expecting
it to print out this entire string right
here hit enter okay let's see what went
wrong is head Bucky desktop and then it
went to a new line and said dude pics no
no I'm trying to get my nude pics let my
food pics pics you don't want to see
what's in there so why is this well you
know how I told you guys that whenever
you use backslash in something after it
means something special well in this
case and in programming whenever you use
backslash n it means go to a new line it
has a special meaning so what this does
is it starts printing this out and it
says okay backslash n bump it to a new
line and then print the rest of it which
is ood picks so that's what did bump to
new line dude pics but of course
whenever we use this in our program it's
going to cause an issue because this is
going to confuse a program so what
happens when you actually want to print
out this right here well what you can do
is right before your first um little
quotation mark
you can put R now what R means is print
out the rostering with no special
meaning just print it out as is whatever
is in between the quotation marks so now
you hit enter and check it out so again
you're going to use the R right before
your strings a lot whenever you're
working with file paths and other stuff
like that
so now that we know the basics of
strings and how to print them out now I
want to show you guys something else
that's well pretty cool in my mind you
can actually add together strings kind
of like you can numbers so let's make a
variable called first name and set it
equal to a string called Bucky and add a
space after it to so now not only can we
store numbers and variables we can also
store strings in variables so what I can
do is say something like this first name
plus another string my last name Roberts
and it's going to say ok whenever you
take a string and add another string to
it check it out
it makes an even longer string so not
only numbers you can also add strings
together and another thing you can do is
this if you take that again and add
another name like mclovin and hit enter
I now have a new last name so that's one
of the uses of how to add strings
together and I want to show you guys
something else cool you're not only
limited to adding shrinks together in
Python what you can do is you can also
multiply strings so if we have first
name which is Bucky and we multiply it
by 5 check out what happens what it does
is it takes that string and it prints it
out five times so this is actually going
to save us a lot of work whenever we
have to print something out repeatedly
like people's names or anything like
that we can actually take a string and
multiply it by some number to print it
out that many times it happens instead
of having to write like five lines of
code so I know that was a lot to take in
but remember escape whenever you have to
use a special character whenever you're
working with file paths use our before
which pretty much means rush string and
you can also perform mathematical
operations on strings a lot like you can
numbers so thank you guys for watching
I'm tired out I'm going to go take a nap
probably just going to eat a hot pocket
but whatever I'll see you guys in the
next video