alright guys welcome to your second
Python tutorial and in this video we're
gonna be learning more about those basic
math operators and also I want to teach
you guys about something called
variables if we have time so in the last
tutorial we saw that you can add two
numbers together three plus four simple
enough now you can also use minus to
subtract that's you know kind of
intuitive however if you never program
before I'll talk to you guys about
multiplication and division whenever you
want to multiply two numbers you use the
asterisks which is above the a on your
keyboard then you can just do 3 times 20
easy enough now whenever you want to
divide use the forward slash so 12 over
4 12 divided by 4 equals 3 now just like
in real life computer programming in
Python also has orders of operation so
say that you had 8 plus 2 multiplied by
10 well you may be thinking ok 8 plus 2
equals 10 10 multiplied by 10 equals 100
okay I got 28 and that's because just
like in real life it follows the orders
of operation and multiplies and divides
first so 2 multiplied by 10 which would
be 20 and then it adds 8 now if you ever
wanted to run this like you thought it
would you can put them in parentheses so
8 plus 2 and again anything in
parentheses happens first takes
precedence over everything else so this
would be 8 plus 2 which is 10 and then
multiply that answer by 10 so again
whenever you want to do that use
parentheses now this is pretty simple
stuff so far however the one thing that
may confuse you is whenever you're using
division and this is not only Python but
all computer programming languages
computers handle a division and the kind
of weird way and you may get some
unexpected results now Python is pretty
good at just simple division so 18 over
4 4 and a half now there are a couple
cool techniques that we can use and this
is actually helpful in a lot of cases
there are some times that we want to
round down or in other words drop this
decimal place
we're gonna say okay eighteen divided by
four
whenever we'll use two forward slashes
what this does is it takes the result
and rounds it down to the nearest whole
number in other words it pretty much
takes the decimal place and drops it
forgets about it
now if we only want to access the
remainder such as 18 I'll show you guys
what I'm doing and then I'll talk you
guys through so what this does is
whenever you use the percent sign
whenever you divide 18 by 4 it's 4 with
2 left over so 16 plus 2 is 18 so what
this does is the modulus it's called the
percent sign it gives you the remainder
simple enough so okay cool division
symbols basic math operations what else
you got
well another cool thing that you can do
with Python is really easily calculate
the powers or um the exponents so say
that you wanted to do 5 to the power of
3 well you can do 5 x 5 x 5 and get 125
or you can do this 5 double asterisks 3
this is pretty much the same thing and
if you hit enter it's pretty much saying
5 to the power of 3 so again double
asterisk means calculate the powers all
right so that's pretty much the core
basics of how to use simple math
operators in Python so now I'll teach
you guys about variables now a variable
is just like a placeholder for something
else just like in math class so you can
take X and you can name your variables
pretty much anything you want make sure
you start them with letters and they can
also include numbers on it don't include
anything like a stupid symbol pretty
much start it with a letter and you can
also have numbers in as well those are
like a very basic rule so let's go ahead
and make a variable name tuna in in
order to set it equal to a certain value
just use the equal sign and then the
value so hit enter and right now we have
a variable called tuna
and it's equal to the value of five so
now we can use it in place of any
equation so for example remember we can
add two numbers together well now we can
add a number plus a variable and this is
essentially saying 20 plus 5 hit enter
pretty cool now you can actually use all
variables in your equations so if you
have tuna equal to five and bacon equal
to 18 then what you can do is put bacon
/ tuna which is pretty much saying okay
18 over five and that is three point six
so if you guys ever wanted to know what
bacon / tuna is is three point six
pretty interesting but now we know the
basic math operators also some cool um
you know extra things like exponents and
stuff and also how to divide bacon over
tuna so in the next video we're going to
be learning some more complex stuff so
thank you guys for watching and I'll see
you then