well well well guys congratulations you
finally found them the greatest place on
tutorials in the entire freaking
universe so before we get started
learning Python making games doing
anything cool like that what I want to
mention is this I'm guessing that you're
watching these videos on either YouTube
or my website and if you try watching
them on that little video player then
it's gonna be hard to see what's going
on so whenever you watch these videos
make sure you change the video size to
full screen and also 1080 high def my
entire desktop is 1080 and I'm gonna be
recording the entire thing so again make
sure to change it to 1080 and also full
screen and these videos are gonna be
crystal clear so now that you're done oh
that simple enough
what is Python now you probably already
know what it is and you just want to
learn it but for some people who are
just watching this video because they
heard of it before but they aren't
really sure what it is it's a
programming language that you can use
for a ton of stuff you can actually use
it not only for like web development but
you can make use it to make computer
games just you know basic software for
the desktop like this crap right here
and you can also use it to make like web
crawlers so say you have a website and
you want to go gather links or go to a
website and download all the images
really easy you can do it for that too
so again there's a bunch of awesome
stuff um regarding Python and that's why
it's one of my favorite actually I will
say it is my favorite programming
language of all time all right so enough
about you know me rambling on talking
about whatever let's go ahead and start
coding so the Python website that you
need to go to is WWI thon org and go to
that this is the home page and once
you're on there go to the download
section so click that and you're gonna
see okay the first thing we have to
decide is whether download Python 2.7
point 8 or the latest one three point
four point one now this is kind of old
and it's becoming outdated so I would
highly recommend downloading Python 3.4
point one
why the heck not now whenever you
download that you're gonna get this
little thing right here or wherever your
downloads go to so depending on what
browser you use you might it may be
different to access your downloads but
if you go to Bucky or your name's not
gonna be Bucky but downloads you're
gonna see you now have a file downloaded
so just double click this and if I ask
you for permission say go ahead let me
close out of this stuff and it says ok
and this is actually one of the easiest
some installers you just clicking next a
bunch of times if you ever insult
anything in your life you know it's
gonna feel like home but install for all
users sure why not next and it says and
this is just because I already
downloaded it before because I don't
know I just like using Python but for
this tutorial
um I uninstalled it just so I could show
you guys had downloaded it so you
probably won't get this but it says do
you want to over it exists files well
yes I do why not
next next and then it installs it's
actually really quick
all right easy enough I mean hey click
like two buttons and now we have Python
alright so completed it finish alright
so uh I guess you have lights on now but
where the heck is it how do you even
start using it well if you go to your
Start menu and go to all programs and
scroll down you're gonna see that you
now have a folder called Python 3.4 so
click that and it has a bunch of crap in
it right now but what we want right now
is this the I D le this is just a nice
little program that lets us test out
things in Python now we can't just click
this right now and it can open up ok
pretty cool but what I want to show you
guys had to do is this we're actually
gonna be using this a lot so go back to
that and if you right click it you can
press send to desktop and then it puts
you or gives you a nice little handy
icon on your desktop so hopefully this
is gonna be one of your most used
programs for the future so now we can
just double click it and boom check it
out
so again this is called the python IDL
II or the Python show and then lets you
test out really simple commands it's
great for learning Python from the
beginning now I'm not gonna be um
actually start teaching you anything in
this command but just so we know that
everything is up and working
just type in a simple equation like 3
plus I don't know 4 why not hit enter it
gives us seven all right so we're good
to go we have everything installed we
added a shortcut to the desktop and now
we all ready to start filling our brains
with Python so thank guys for watching
don't forget to subscribe in the next
tutorial we're gonna start learning the
code