[Music]
hey guys welcome to the first video of
my web development for absolute
beginners series this entire series is
meant for anyone wanting to learn basic
web design and web development and
there's absolutely no prerequisites I'm
teaching this course as if I'm talking
to someone that's never written a line
of HTML before so don't worry about
having any kind of prior web development
knowledge this will be an ongoing course
or ongoing series and each video will
focus on a different topic so in this
particular video we're going to be
focusing on HTML only then we'll move on
to CSS and possibly some JavaScript I
also want to show you how to upload a
website to the Internet alright so just
a couple things before we begin so I
want to stress that this this course and
this this video the series is for
beginners okay if you've been a
subscriber for a while I can almost
guarantee that you're going to know
everything in this video and in this
year well maybe not in the series but in
this video at least you know if you've
been building websites and you're going
to know the basics I'm doing a series
like this because I don't really feel
like I have a place to start on my
channel for absolute beginners people
that that really don't know anything
about web development so hopefully my my
advanced programmers that are that have
subscribed to me can understand that and
just know that you know this isn't going
to be an ongoing thing for you know for
the next 20 videos it's just this series
all right also there's going to be
little to no CSS in this particular
video that's going to be covered most
likely in the next video and just to
warn you HTML without CSS is very very
ugly we're not focusing on the style at
all here we're focusing on HTML syntax
all right so we will be sticking to
html5 I don't want to confuse anybody by
you know throwing in standards from HTML
4 or XHTML or any other derivative
anything like that so we're going to
stick to HTML 5 only so we will be
working with examples we'll be building
a cheat sheet but we're also going to
take a look at some slides along the way
all right now you're not going to learn
HTML or anything for that matter in five
or 10 minutes I've actually seen videos
called you know learn HTML in five
minutes and
and that's just absolute if
you're going to be a web developer you
have to be patient and you have to you
have to really enjoy learning because
you're going to be learning even when
you land a good job you're going to be
learning every single day so try and be
patient try to follow along I know
people can get a little aggravated with
videos that are over like you know 25
minutes but you know if you if you're
that impatient where you can't watch an
hour-long course then you're probably in
the wrong profession and I don't mean to
sound harsh or anything but I don't want
to scare anybody down the wrong path and
I really do mean that wholeheartedly
alright so enough with the preference
let's go ahead and get started so what
is HTML it stands for hypertext markup
language and a lot of people just
starting out don't realize that HTML is
not a programming language at any level
it's a markup language for creating web
pages and documents ok HTML documents
one of the key elements of a programming
language is logic so you can have things
like conditionals where you can say if
this is true then do this HTML however
doesn't have any of that hTML is used to
just display in format elements of a web
page that may be a text paragraph or a
heading a bullet list or an image or
many other things it's strictly
presentational just try to remember that
there's no logic there's no actual
programming so an example of a
programming language would be JavaScript
or PHP or c-sharp
these are intricate languages and
they're responsible for things like
connecting to a database you know for
like an online store or something like
that user login dynamic functionality
things like that
now with that said that doesn't make any
programming language more important than
HTML in fact if you're getting into web
development HTML in at least in my
opinion is much more important because
hTML is the building block of the web
every single site that you see outputs
HTML to the browser no matter what kind
of advanced programming it uses on the
back end all right you can build a
website using just HTML and CSS CSS of
course as a styling language and we'll
get into that in another video but you
can have just an HTML site without any
any JavaScript or any PHP or anything
like that it will be purely
presentational you can't have like an
online
store or anything with just HTML but you
can have a basic business website with
you know information about the company
and so on now it is hotter these days to
get a job with just HTML and CSS
knowledge but you can do it there are
still companies that are that are you
know purchasing websites that are
strictly presentational all right so I
don't want to spend too much time on
this stuff so let's move on to what we
actually need to get started so to get
started building websites you only
really need two things you need a
browser to view the HTML and you need a
text editor to write the HTML now don't
worry about what kind of computer you
have if you're on Windows Mac or Linux
it doesn't matter as long as you have
these two things everything that I'm
doing in this in a series and then this
video is completely cross-platform so
for a browser can be whatever you want
I'd highly suggest Google Chrome it's
the fastest and in my opinion it's the
best for any web developer but of course
you can use Firefox or Safari even edge
just please for god sakes don't use
internet explorer if you're using
something less than Windows 10 please
download a different browser all right
so you can also use any text editor you
want which one and which one is up to
you you could even use Windows notepad
but I wouldn't suggest it you want to
use something with line numbers and
syntax highlighting stuff like that I'm
going to be using an editor called
sublime text which is available for
Windows Mac and Linux so we feel free to
download it I'm going to show you where
and how to download it I'm using sublime
text because it's very simple it's very
light when I'm working with other
technologies and languages I usually use
something called Adam or Visual Studio
code but I think that those are overkill
for what we're doing here so before we
move on let's go ahead and install
sublime text so that we can start
writing HTML alright guys so you want to
go to www.hsn
if you want it if you want to use
something else that's fine now this
program is free to try if you want to
keep using it that's just buying a
license if you use it without a license
it doesn't have any limitations or
anything like that you're just going to
get a pop up every once in a while that
says you should probably buy a license
alright so let's go ahead and download
this I'm going to click the big download
button here alright so once that's done
we can go ahead and open it it's just
going to be a simple
Staller for windows and of course you
can grab this for mac or linux so let's
go through this default location is fine
I'm going to choose to add it to the
Explorer context menu what that will do
is it'll allow us to right-click on an
HTML file and say open it open with
sublime text so we definitely want that
checked and that we're just going to
install alright so it should be all set
let's click finish and now we should be
able to open it up I'm just going to
search for it down here my search bar if
it opens and let's just see right here
sublime text 3 ok there's also sublime
text 2 but 3 obviously is the newer
version alright so this is what a text
editor looks like I'm not going to go
through all the features I just want to
strictly focus on HTML syntax so now
that we have our editor installed we can
go ahead and we can start to create our
HTML file so one great thing about hTML
is we don't need any kind of special
server or hosting company to write and
test HTML you can simply create a file
right on your computer you can give it a
dot HTML extension and you can open it
up with your browser now when your site
is ready to deploy to the Internet you
will need to buy a domain name you'll
need a hosting package and then you'll
need to upload everything to your web
host ok and I'll get into that in a
later video but for now we can build our
site or build our cheat sheet locally
without that stuff so to create an HTML
file it has to have an HTML extension
you can call it whatever you want you
just have to end it with dot HTML this
will allow it to be displayed correctly
in a web browser now one thing to
remember that your home page should
always be called index.html if you go to
a domain like let's say W W something
calm and you upload a file called
index.html that's the file that's going
to show on that root domain ok if you
upload a file let's say about dot HTML
that's going to show when you go to
something calm slash about dot HTML so
the index file will always be the root
file of the home page unless of course
you're messing with server settings and
you change it but by default that's
that's the behavior it's going to look
at index.html
alright guys so we're going to go ahead
and create our first HTML file now I'm
going to put the
in a folder so I'm going to create a
folder I'm going to call this HTML cheat
sheet okay and then inside that folder
let's create a new file by going to new
text document and we're going to call
this index dot HTML okay we'll just say
yes we want to change the file extension
and notice that mine has a chrome icon
by default because Chrome is my default
browser and that's what opens up the
HTML file yours may be different now if
you if you're using Windows you may have
an issue where you don't see the dot
HTML okay if you're not seeing that what
you want to do is you want to go to view
options change folder and search options
all right you want to go to view and
then down here you want to uncheck hide
extensions for known file types okay you
want to make sure that's unchecked and
then click apply and then you're going
to see the extension and it may say
something like index.html dot txt just
make sure you get rid of the dot text
all right I'm sure most of you know that
but just in case there's people that
don't alright so what we want to do now
is we want to open this with sublime
text so we can actually just right click
and say open with sublime text let me
just bring it over it opened up on a
different screen and that's going to
open it up you can see up in the tab it
says index.html now another thing you
could have done is you could just go to
file open and you could find that on
your computer that HTML file and open it
alright so now that we have that open
what I'm going to do is just type in
hello world here just text no tags or
anything yet and you want to make sure
you save it so you can either go to file
save or you can just hit ctrl s which is
what I would suggest it's much quicker
and then it saves okay now what we want
to do is open it up so let's go ahead
and let's open it up with Chrome and
that's the default so all I have to do
is double click and then that's going to
open it up in the Chrome browser and you
can see it says hello world
all right so even if we put just text in
here with no HTML tags at all it's still
going to show the text in the browser
all right now what I'm going to do is
just snap this to the edge here and then
we're going to just going to open up
sublime text on this side and I'm going
to make sublime a little bit bigger than
the browser for now
just so we can see everything all the
code and I just want to talk a little
bit about HTML tags
so when HTML tag is the basic building
block of any webpage different tags
format the way that information and text
is displayed so element names are
surrounded in angle brackets are greater
than and less than symbols and tags
usually come in pairs one to start tag
ones an end tag we look over here we
have a start tag the end tag and then we
have content in between all right in
this example here we have about us as
the content of the text and it's
surrounded in h1 tags which stands for
heading 1 and I'm going to get into the
specific tags later on all right here's
another example with a paragraph tag and
we just have the text this is a
paragraph now notice with the BR tag
here there's no opening and close it's
just one tag this is called a self
closing tag and these are basically tags
that don't have any content within them
okay notice that the slash is actually
after the element ok so BR slash it's
after and this is kind this is an XHTML
style so we don't really need to do this
in html5 you can if you want but you can
just use just simply BR okay and BR is a
line break tag so it's just basically
going to push it down a line and there's
no reason to have any content like this
inside of a line break so that's why
it's considered a self closing tag
alright now there's a very specific
structure to an HTML document so this is
a quick diagram I just want to look at
you'll see that we have everything is
surrounded in HTML tags we have the
start and ending tag inside that we have
a head area and we have a body area now
the head has nothing to do with the
output that's in the browser the head
has things like the page title it has
things like links to CSS files and
JavaScript files that you want to use
metadata such as the description and
keywords things like that the
description and keywords are actually
used by search engines like Google so
that it knows some more information
about what's what's actually on the web
page alright and then in the body we
have the actual markup that's going to
display in the browser so headings text
images
things like that now this is an example
of a very simple web page notice that we
have the HTML tags the head the body we
also have this thing at the top this is
a doctype and it's not technically an
HTML tag it's just a declaration and it
should always be the first thing on the
web page and what this does is it tells
the browser what type of HTML this is
actually written in now this is the
standard doctype for html5 ok let's take
a look at some of the other ones so as I
said this is html5 if you were using
HTML 4.0 point R 4.0 1 it would have to
be a doctype like this and you start
getting into different different types
whether it's strict or transitional and
it can get very complicated same thing
with XHTML I'm not going to get into
that because I don't want to confuse you
guys we're going to just stick with
html5 just know that other doc types are
a lot more complicated alright guys so
we're going to get started on the
structure of our HTML document so I made
this bigger so there's no no doubt that
you guys can see this I'm going to get
rid of the hello world here and like I
said the first thing we want to put in
here is the doctype so we want to put an
angle bracket or a less span and then an
exclamation and then we just want the
word doctype usually in all caps and
then HTML and then the closing bracket
okay so this is the official doctype for
html5 after that we want to put in our
HTML tags ok that's going to wrap
everything now notice in sublime
when I think when I put the angle
bracket and then when as soon as I hit
the backslash or so I'm sorry a forward
slash it actually gives us the ending
tag automatically so we don't have to
type it out all right another thing we
can do is let's say for the head tag
here we can just put the text head and
click tab and it will give us both the
beginning and the end tag all right so
just a helpful shortcut in sublime and
moat and most um text editors at that
alright so in addition to the head we
need the body so let's go ahead and put
the body tags in alright now in the head
all I want is the title so let's go
ahead and do that and we'll say HTML
can't spell cheatsheet
save that and then over here I'm going
to reload and notice there's nothing in
the actual browser here because we have
nothing in the body but if you look at
the tab you'll see it says HTML cheat
sheet ok so whatever we put in the title
here is going to show in this tab now a
lot of times when you're building
websites you're going to want to see the
exact source code that's running in the
browser and for that we can do a control
U and this is going to show us the exact
HTML that's being parsed now what we're
doing here is building us just a static
HTML site so it's going to look exactly
like this but when you're using
languages like let's say PHP where you
have dynamic programming that's kind of
generating the HTML for you from
variables and things like that this is
very helpful because you can see the
exact HTML that's being parsed and you
can't see it in your actual code alright
so another thing that is very helpful in
chrome and other browsers is the
developer tools so if we hit f12 we get
this little console down here and
there's different things here there's
JavaScript console there's networking so
you can see how what pages are loading
and so on there's a lot of advanced
stuff here but for now we're just going
to look at the elements tab which just
shows the HTML we don't have anything in
the body but if we did we could hover
over things and it'll actually give it a
highlight up here which is very helpful
and you can even edit stuff down here
which I might get into later all right
it's not going to stick if you get it
down here but it will for you know until
the page is refreshed so let's go back
to our body over here and we're going to
start to look at some tags so we're
going to start with headings now before
we go into tags I just want to mention
comment so with HTML you can have these
comments with the less than exclamation
and then two hyphens and then let's give
it just a comment we'll just say this is
where our headings are going to go and
then we want to end the comment with
devil - and then greater than now this
is not going to be parsed by the browser
if I save this and reload you're not
going to see it show up here because
it's a comment ok it's treated as it's
just for the the developer to see all
right now when it comes to headings
there's six different tags we can use we
have H
1 through h6 all right so let's go ahead
and put an h1 in here and I'm just going
to say heading 1 and save and let's
reload and notice that it gives it a
bigger text ok so the browser by default
has some core styling in it and an h1 is
going to make the text bigger it's also
going to add some padding around the
edges so that you know but the next
piece of content will be pushed down a
little all right so that's an h1 and
that's the biggest heading there is ok
so let's take a look at an h2 so we'll
say heading 2 and save that and you'll
see that it's a little smaller notice
the padding in between the two alright
so what I'll do now is just copy this
and let's do 3 4 5 6 ok so this will be
an h3 4 5 & 6 this will be 3 4 5 & 6 and
we're just going to change these as well
all right now I want you guys to have
this to look back on if you need it
whoops 2 3 4 5 & 6 all right so let's go
ahead and save and reload the browser
and you'll see the different sizes of
the headings now you can change the
sizes of these texts through CSS which
you know we're going to get into
probably in the next video of the series
where we can change the font we can
change the size whatever you'd like you
could even make all these headings the
same size through CSS all right so the
next thing we're going to look at our
paragraphs so to put a comment here
we'll say paragraph and a paragraph is
just P okay it's just a P tag now I'm
going to give you a little hint in
sublime if you ever want to generate
dummy text which is just kind of just
sample text to use for development you
can actually just type in larom the word
larom and then tab and that's going to
give you some lorem ipsum now if you
wanted a certain amount of words like
let's say we wanted 10 words you could
say warm 10 tab oops I guess you can't
do that in sublime I actually haven't
used sublime in a while I usually use
atom or visual studio code and you can
do that there I'm not sure why it
doesn't work here
but anyways we'll just generate some
text and we'll save that and a paragraph
just like the headings has some default
styling okay so for one for one it has a
display block which means it's a block
level element so if we were to take
another paragraph and go ahead and paste
that in and reload you'll see that it's
automatically on a new line it also has
some margin okay it has I believe one
eeehm of margin or one M and M is a
measurement in CSS just like pixels
except it's used for more responsive
stuff so if we hit f12 and look at the
developer tools I'm just going to make
this a little bigger and we look down in
elements now you can see we can hover
over everything and it'll show us it up
top and if we look at the paragraph here
and I just click on it over here you'll
actually see any CSS or any styling that
is associated with this particular
paragraph or whatever tag we're hovering
over and when you see this user agent
stylesheet this is the default browser
styling so you can see a paragraph is
displayed as a block so it's block level
and then it actually has some default
margin now I'm not going to talk about
margin and padding and stuff too much in
this video because this is strictly HTML
margin and padding is CSS okay so this
is going to be very little to no CSS in
this video but just know that margin is
spacing around the element okay and
you'll see that there's this before and
after is actually the top and bottom so
that's why you see this space right here
it's actually 1m okay or 1 a.m. which is
a measurement in CSS so we do have
margin on the top and bottom by default
okay and then zero pixels on the start
and end which is the left and right of
the paragraph and it even gives us a
little diagram here you'll see we have
the power graph and if you look up in
the body it shows it highlighted padding
which there isn't any border and then
the margin and you actually see the
margin highlighted up above okay so this
is really helpful again I couldn't
imagine doing web development without
without the chrome tools now tags can
either be in line or block level element
so inline tags or inline elements do not
start a new line when you use
okay they take only the necessary with
they need block level elements however
start a new line and they take the full
width of that line so if this is
confusing don't worry about it I will
give you some examples block level
elements include tags like div heading
or heading sorry h1 through h6
paragraphs form inline elements includes
spans images links and I'm going to go
over all this stuff in a little bit but
just know that some tags are block level
some are inline so let's go into our
paragraph here and I'm going to add some
other tags here okay and these are all
going to be inline they're not going to
make us start a new line when we use
them so let's take a look at strong ok
so strong is basically you want to
surround something and say that this
text should be strong in some way now by
default it's going to be bold so if we
save this and I reload you'll see that
the text we surrounded the strong tags
with is actually going to be bold by
default but that doesn't necessarily
mean that it has to be bold you can grab
on to this from within your CSS and you
can change the font size you can make it
italic whatever you want to do just know
that it's a semantic tag for for making
the text stick out ok and this is
usually this will usually replace the
old bold tags which are not semantic at
all and not recommended anymore okay
same thing with e/m okay so ii m is for
emphasized okay so let's surround this
text right here with e/m and we'll save
and reload and again by default it's
going to be hopelessly put to space
there by default it's going to be italic
okay so you'll see right here but again
you can grab on to this in CSS and you
can change it to whatever style you want
it just basically means that this part
of the the document should be emphasized
so this text should be emphasized
alright so now let's take a look at
links so what I'm going to do is I'll go
let's go to the second paragraph here
and let's say we want to wrap this text
in a link to go to either another page
on our site or an external website so a
link is actually an a tag so let's say a
and we're going to give it an attribute
I'm going to talk
attributes in a second okay but let's
surround this text here all right and
then if I save that and reload notice
over here we now have this text as a
link now the href attribute is going to
be the location that we want this link
to open and this could be either local
it could be let's say if we had an about
dot HTML page on our site or it could be
external so if we want to put HTTP will
say google.com and if I save that we go
over here and we click on that link it's
going to open google.com now notice it
opens it on the same page usually when
you have an external website you don't
want the user to just leave your site
like that so what you could do is you
could add another attribute called
target and one of the values for this is
underscore blank and that's going to
open up a new tab with this site so if
we save reload and click this notice
that Google opens on a new tab and we
still have our site right here okay so
it stops the user from having to leave
your site okay and you usually only want
to use target blank if it's an external
site if you're going to another page on
your website you don't want that to
happen you don't want all these tabs
opening up when you're just navigating
the site so all HTML tags can have
something called an attribute or
multiple attributes and what they do is
they provide more information about a
certain element for instance the href
provided in the link we just did we
created an a tag with an href and what
the href does is as you saw is it opens
up or directs it to a certain location a
certain website link okay we also
provided the target attribute which is
not required but it still allowed us to
make it so that the link opened in
another tab all right now attributes are
always placed at the start tag and
they're always formatted as key value
pairs okay the actual attribute itself
such as href our target as we saw that's
the key and then whatever the value is
all right so we have the attribute name
or the attribute key and then the value
now the value is always going to be in
quotes you can use double quotes or
single quotes I would suggest double
quotes because that's that's
usually what's used that's most popular
alright guys so let's get back to our
HTML so we're going to go below the
paragraphs that we just created and now
I'm going to show you something called a
list okay
so there's basically two kinds of Lists
as an unordered list and an ordered list
so let's start with an unordered list
which is a UL tag so in the UL we need
to have list items okay a list is
basically like a bullet point a bullet
point list so each list item is going to
have an li tag and then in here we can
put whatever we want let's just put the
text list item 1 okay and then I'm just
going to copy this and we'll go ahead
and we'll put four of them in so say
let's tie them one two three four and
doesn't matter what you put inside here
well let's go ahead and save that and
reload and notice that we have bullet
points now for our list items it also
adds some default padding notice that
this is pushed over by default and if we
go ahead and open up our chrome tools
and exit to make it a little bigger
there we go so over here let's hover
over ul and you'll see that there's
actually some default styling from user
Asian style sheet which is the basically
just the browser default so it's
displayed as a block okay it has a list
style type of disk which you can change
within the CSS if you want to have a
different kind of bullet point it adds
some margin okay
actually yeah it adds margin before and
after one one M and then also adds 40
pixels of padding on the start which is
the left okay so it pushes it over 40
pixels and of course you can overwrite
this from within your CSS if you want to
change that you can also remove the
bullet points you can do whatever you
want as far as styling but that's we're
not getting into that just yet alright
so that is an unordered list now we also
have an ordered list which is an oil tax
so what I'll do is just copy this and
I'm just going to change it to an oh L
instead of a ul okay we'll save that
reload and notice that the ordered list
now gets rid of the bullet points and
replaces it with the numbers
okay so it'll automatically add numbers
to your list now unordered lists are
usually what's used for website
navigation when you see a nav bar up at
the top that's usually just an unordered
list it's just styled so that the
elements float you know float to this to
the right they're displayed inline and
it has some really nice background
colors and things like that but the H as
far as the HTML goes it's usually just a
simple list all right so next thing
we're going to look at our tables so
let's put a comment here and we'll just
say table so it's going to be a table
tag all right and there's quite a few
tags that go into building a table so we
have a table and then we have a head an
area for the heading and then an area
for the table body so we say tea head
okay and then we're going to have tea
body now in the heading is where we're
going to put the row that has like you
know if we're going to have a name email
and age column alright so these will be
the headings of each columns so we're
going to put a TR okay TR is table row
and then each heading is going to have a
th tag alright so this will be let's say
name we'll put another one this will be
email and let's say age okay so these
are the headings now if I save this and
reload this is what it's going to look
like by default now I'm going to do
something here because I don't want you
guys to have to keep looking at the
bottom of the screen so what I'm going
to do is just put in a div right here
with a style attribute you don't have to
do this I just want to move this stuff
down I'm just going to put a margin top
of 500 pixels all right and that's just
going to make it so that I can put this
so you guys can look in the middle now
not at the bottom alright so back to our
table we have our tea head with our
table row and our headings now we want
another TR okay and this time we're not
going to use th because these aren't
headings anymore this is actual data so
we're going to use TD okay so let's say
we want to name just put my name and
then we'll put another TD with an email
we'll just say Brad add
something calm and then we'll put age
put 35 save that reload and now we have
some data inside of our table okay and
you're most likely going to have more
than one row so what I'll do is copy
that
oops paste it in two times and let's
just change the name up here we'll say
John Doe say 45 and then change this
will say Sara Williams and flips will
make her 25
all right so we'll reload and now we
have a couple names and again this is
going to look very ugly because we're
not we don't have any CSS whatsoever
it's just HTML markup okay and this is
what a default table looks like now the
way that we build HTML websites has
changed along the way along the past few
years okay we used to use tables to
actually create website layouts for
instance you have a sidebar and then the
main area and then another sidebar and
that could actually be a table with a
couple columns that is not recommended
anymore you don't want to use tables for
anything for your layout you want to use
tables for tabular data only so if you
have like a list of customers with their
names and info like this that's fine to
use a table but do not use it for your
layout you want to use CSS for your
website layout all right that that's
very 1999 ish to use tables for layouts
okay and there's there's little rules
like that that they're not enforced by
the browser per se or by the technology
but it's just there's a right and a
wrong way to do things and I'm a big
advocate for you know doing things
differently and not everyone not being
the same but just some things are just
wrong and using tabular using tables for
for a layout is wrong all right so now
we're going to move on to forms okay
which you see a lot of on the internet
now the important thing to know about
forms is that with HTML we can create
the actual look of the form but we can't
add
functionality to the forum with HTML for
instance a login form you can build the
actual look of the form of HTML but to
actually make it function you need to
have something like PHP or some other
programming language with dynamic
functionality all right so we're only
covering the look of the form so we're
going to put in a form tag all right now
usually with a form you'll see an
attribute called action and that's going
to basically submit the form to a
certain page for instance a PHP page so
let's say it was going to go to a file
called processed PHP on our server and
maybe that would be a newsletter form or
a register form something like that
you'll also see method and Method is
usually going to be post or a form this
meaning that we're making a post request
to the server and posts are used to do
things like add data to a database stuff
like that it's it's it's pretty secure
as opposed to get which is going to
submit it and with a get request you'll
actually see the data filled in in the
URL and it's not very safe but it's fine
for things like search things where
you're not actually adding data or
something to a server alright but that's
a lot more advanced we're not going to
get into that now ok I will leave this
here but just know that this is this has
to do with more advanced server-side
programming so in our form let's go
ahead and let's add a label ok so we're
going to have a couple inputs we're
going to put a label for I would say
first name all right and then under that
let's put an input tag so an input is
going to have an attribute called type
because there's a lot of different
inputs this is actually going to be a
text input okay which is probably the
most common and then the name attribute
has to do with again server-side
programming if we were submitting this
to a PHP file this name attribute is how
we would grab the value of this form
that's submitted ok so it's not going to
make any difference to us what we put
here but I'm just going to put first -
name alright so let's go ahead and save
that reload and this is what we get
now this is awfully close to the table
so I'm going to do is put a line break
here usually two separate things like
this we would use CSS but I'm not
getting into CSS yet so let's just put a
line break that's going to push it down
a little bit
all right we also have an HR tag which I
haven't talked about yet which is a
horizontal rule and that gives us kind
of a line in our brows in our page so if
I reload you'll see we now have a line
that goes across the page I'm just going
to put another BR under it as well all
right so just separates allows us to
separate things so let's create another
field here on our form let's do a last
name so what I'll do is copy this and
let's just change this to last name name
last name actually you know what usually
what I do here is use camel case so
we'll go like this instead of the -
camel case is basically starting it with
a lower case and then every other word
every word after that is going to be
upper case so now we have a first name
and a last name if I reload you'll see
it down here now labels and inputs of
both inline that's why they're on the
same line here and they only take up the
amount of width that that element takes
up usually you'll have form form fields
you know on separate lines so what I'm
going to do is wrap them in a div
because remember divs are block level
elements so that'll actually put it on
the next line look alright so let's do
that and then we'll put a div here wrap
that around both the label and the input
okay so now if we reload now they're on
separate lines they're still pretty
close together like I said we would use
CSS to add some padding there but I'm
just going to put a line break in
between the two okay all right so let's
look at some of the other types of field
now you may want an email let's put a
line break there so for email you could
of course use text just change this you
could use text but with each with html5
we now have a type that we can use
called email
and that'll actually add a little bit of
validation without having to add any
JavaScript to anything if we try to
submit our form and it's not a valid
email address and we have the type of
email it's going to give us a little
error that pops up all right so you want
to use type email when you're dealing
with an email address all right so let's
say let's copy that and let's put let's
say message so what I want to do here is
I want to use a text area which is kind
of like a bigger text input so for that
we don't actually use an input tag
there's an actual text area tag okay so
we'll go like that and usually your text
area if you're submitting to you know to
a server-side file you'll have a name so
we'll call it message all right we'll
save that reload and now we have a text
area okay and you can actually make it
bigger and smaller with this little
control here another field that that
you'll see quite a bit is a select list
okay so for that I'm just going to copy
this div so let's say this is I don't
know we'll just say gender I guess so
let's say we want a select list to
choose either male or female
so we'll put a select we'll give it a
name of gender okay now each select is
going to have and it's going to have a
couple options so that'll be the option
tag and then usually you'll have a value
associated with each option so let's say
male okay and then the actual text to be
displayed will go in here like that
all right so let's save that's coming
copy that and just to be politically
correct we'll go ahead and do another so
this will be female and this will be
other
all right so if we save that and reload
now we have a little select list with
male/female other for gender all right
now we have a couple other few of field
types that I want to show you but I'm
just going to paste these in because
they're kind of running out of time here
so I'm going to go right under this div
and I'm going to paste in a couple more
so this is actually a number type so
we're putting an age here with the type
of number and it has a name and then I
also added a value here because we can
also add a predefined value to our
inputs all right and then we also have
the type of date okay so this is
actually a date selector and these are
these are html5 okay so these are both
html5 standards so let's save that and
reload and now if you have a number and
actually has these arrows where we can
switch we can make the number go up and
down and then the date you'll see we
have this date selector okay now like I
said we can have a value we can put a
value to anything we want here now
before html5 if you wanted to have like
for instance we'll put a value here and
we'll just say let's say we wanted to
say enter first name okay and reload
usually you know before each shell five
we would have to do this I'm going to
use JavaScript to make it so that when
we clicked in here this would go away
okay and that was that was a real pain
in the ass
so with html5 they actually added a
placeholder that we could use here okay
so we'll say placeholder equals into
first-name and now you'll see that it's
grayed out and if I click in here we can
actually replace it okay so that that
made things a lot easier so the last
thing we would need for the form is an
input button so let's go down to the
bottom here and what I'm going to do is
put in an input and we're going to say
type submit okay and we'll give it a
name of submit and it's also going to
need a value which is going to be the
actual text of the button which will be
submit all right so we'll reload and now
we have a submit button okay it's going
to put it's going to actually get
submitted to processed PHP because
that's what we put in the act
of the forum but that doesn't actually
exist okay now we can also have buttons
outside of forms so let's go under the
form I'm just going to put a comment
here and there's a button tag okay so
we'll put a button tag here and we'll
just say click me now this isn't going
to do anything if we reload it's going
to show the button but it's not going to
do anything because in order to hook up
a button to actually do something you
need to use JavaScript okay so what you
would do is you would add an event like
click equals and then you have some
function but we're not going to get into
that that's something for another video
okay we're just focusing on HTML here
and as you can see HTML isn't doesn't
really do much as far as you know
functionality and dynamic that that's
why it's not a programming language it's
a markup language that's just used to
display stuff on the screen and then use
other languages like JavaScript to make
it dynamic alright so the next thing I
want to look at our images or the image
tag okay so for images we're going to
use an IMG tag and this is actually a
self closing tag we don't need to do
slash image or anything like that you
see it doesn't even sublime text doesn't
even do it for us automatically
alright now an image tag by itself means
nothing because it doesn't know what
image to load so let's go ahead and grab
an image just going to search for sample
image we'll grab this bird here okay
whoops I mean to do that we'll just save
it and I'm going to save it into where
is this I think it's on my desktop yeah
HTML cheat sheet and let's uh let's save
it as just sample dot jpg all right and
then what we'll do is go to our image
and we'll say source ok source attribute
and we're going to set this to the name
of the image which is sample dot jpg all
right and then we'll go back to our HTML
reload and now we have the image now the
reason it
the reason it knows where to look is
because this is actually in the same
folder as our index.html so we don't
have to put any folder names or anything
here so what I'm going to do is open up
our folder and you can see that it's in
the same file in the same directory so
usually when you build websites you'll
have a folder called images or IMG or
something like that and then you'll have
your images inside there now if I reload
we're going to it's not going to show
the image because it doesn't it's
looking in the root here but it's really
in the images folder so what we would
have to do is change the location here
to go to images slash sample JPEG and we
reload and now it's back all right now
with images you should also use an alt
attribute and basically what this does
is if it can't find the image it's going
to display whatever text is here so
let's just say my sample image okay now
if I if I save and reload we're not
going to see any difference but if for
some reason it can't find the image
let's just change the name and save and
reload now you'll see that it'll display
the text so you see you have a way to
kind of show what this image is even if
it doesn't even if it doesn't load or it
can't find it all right let's just
change that back all right now there's
also a width and height attribute you
can use an HTML usually I would suggest
using CSS to do this stuff but it is
available so let's say we wanted this to
be say 200 pixels and reload it'll
change it to 200 pixels notice that
images are also inline that's why it's
not on a new line so what I'm going to
do here is just put a line break have to
put it up I put it below the image
all right and notice that the height is
set to auto okay so the height is Auto
so the image still looks good but if you
wanted to change the height up you could
do that as well so let's say change it
to 50 and reload and it'll distort it
but it will change it to what you set it
to but I'm just going to keep the height
I'm just going to get rid of the height
so it's Auto now if you wanted to you
could wrap a link around the image
let's put an A here alright and then you
could actually point to the location of
the image so we'll just grab this put
that in the href and reload and now if I
click on the image it's going to open it
up in the browser
okay browsers don't just open up HTML
files they can open up other types such
as an image all right so we're almost
done with the basic HTML tags and I want
to move on to html5 semantic tags but
last thing I want to show you is
quotations okay so we have different
quotation elements we can use so it's a
quotation and those are blockquote
abbreviate and cite okay so let's start
with blockquote and this is usually used
just for that for some kind of quote so
let's put in a blockquote tag and this
takes an attribute called site and this
is going to be from you know from where
the quote comes from let's say it comes
from traversing mediacom and we'll just
put some sample text in here I'll say
LARM tabs and we'll save that and you'll
see that it does add a little bit of
styling it gives it some padding and
pushes it to the middle a little bit
it's not going to show the actual site
okay if we look at the source code it
will so if we go down right here you'll
see it does show it here all right and
you can style this however you want from
within CSS we also have the abbr tag or
abbreviation tag so let's say we have a
paragraph here and we'll say the I'll
say the www
is awesome all right now this we all
know stands for World Wide Web so what
I'm going to do is just wrap this in an
ad BR tag and we're going to give it a
title and we'll say World Wide Web okay
so it's used for abbreviations so let's
go ahead and save that reload and now
notice that it has an underlined if we
go when we hover it it'll show us the
full the full title okay we also have a
site tag AC ite so let's put another
paragraph here and let's say HTML crash
course by Brad Travis II okay and then
we'll just wrap HTML crash course in a
site tag okay we'll save that reload and
it gives us this italic style here
alright and it lets its semantic to let
the browser know that this is something
that's being cited alright so those are
the basic HTML tags and elements now
what I want to do is talk a little bit
about html5 semantic tags so the html5
semantic tags clearly describe their
meaning to both the browser and the
developer so if we look over here these
are the tags that were added and this is
kind of a diagram of what you would use
these for okay you use them to kind of
lay out your website so if header which
obviously would be the header usually
have your logo things like that your
social media links then we have the nav
tag which would be your nav bar section
okay section would describe like the
copy text or something like that on your
home page or whatever and then if you
have like a blog you could have an
article tag around each post in the blog
a side has to do with just like sidebar
content alright and then you have the
footer which is going to be your you
know your copyright or your your privacy
policy links things like that
okay so html5 created these tags to kind
of structure your document even further
alright guys so what we're going to do
is we're going to create a new HTML page
and we're going to use these html5
semantic tags
map out our page so let's go to let's
see HTML cheat sheet folder we have our
index page where I'm going to create a
new text document and I'm going to call
this blog blog dot HTML okay so we'll
say this is kind of a you know like a
blog blog page or a news page something
like that so let's open that up with
sublime text just bring that over
alright and just like with the index
page we need to have our doctype our
HTML head tags things like that
now with sublime text is actually a
shortcut we can do and that's to do HTML
tab and it'll give us kind of a default
structure so just a nice little shortcut
now in the title let's just say we'll
just say my blog alright we're going to
add some other stuff in the head in a
little bit as well but let's go ahead
and start with our html5 semantic tags
so first thing we're going to do is have
a header alright and in the header we're
just going to have an h1 and we'll just
say my website okay again this is going
to look very ugly because they're not
using CSS but just structurally you want
to have your header at the top all right
then what we'll do is have a section
okay so this would be like the the main
area of the web of the page so if this
were like an about page we could have a
couple paragraphs about the company or
whatever this is a blog blog page so
what we're going to do is we're going to
have some article tags and then in each
article will be each blog post okay so
let's go ahead and put in h3 here that
would be that the title will just say
blog post one alright and then another
attack that I haven't showed you yet is
the small tag and small is usually used
for like create dates things like that
just like sub content so let's just stay
posted by Brad on July 17 okay so let's
save that and take a look real quick so
we're going to go up here in our browser
and we're going to just change
index.html to blog
dot html' all right that's what it's
going to look like and by default the
small tags will actually make the text
smaller so let's put the actual post
which will put it inside of a paragraph
so I'm going to type larom tab gives us
some sample content all right and then
usually on your main blog page you'll
have more than one article what I'm
going to do is I'm going to give this a
class of post okay so each article will
have a class of post and then let's just
copy this and we'll just paste in a
couple more okay this one will be blog
post two and blog post three all right
so if we save that reload now we have a
couple of blog posts you may also have a
link at the bottom of each one that goes
to the full the full post so let's just
put put an a tag and it would go to
something like you know post dot HTML or
something like that and then we'll say
read more okay and then let's just copy
that go one here and here all right and
since a paragraph is a block level
element it's going to go on to the next
line even though an a tag is in line
since the one before is a block level
it's going to push it to the next line
now you may want to have some kind of
sidebar on your page with like let's say
the blog post categories so what we'll
do is go outside of the section and
we're going to put an aside or a side
whatever you want to call it okay and
then in here let's say these are
categories so we'll put an h3 will say
categories and let's put a UL with some
allies with some links so let's say this
we'll just put these two go to a number
sign which basically just means the same
page we're on it's not going to go
anywhere
so we'll say category one will copy that
and we'll say category two and three and
we'll save it reload and now we have our
categories now usually you'd use CSS to
probably float these to the
side rather than have them down here but
that's something we'll get into later
all right now usually when you have some
kind of navigation you want to use the
html5 nav tags so what we would do is
just surround the UL in the navs okay
and we can grab onto this within the CSS
and style it if we want and then finally
we're just going to have the footer so
let's go outside of the aside and put in
a footer tag and we're just going to put
a power graph we'll say copy right now
within HTML you also have these entities
you can use our symbols and there's
different codes for each one so for a
copyright we can do ampere stamp copy
semicolon and that will give us a
copyright symbol all right we'll say
2017 and we'll just say my website okay
we'll save it reload and now we have
copyright 2017 my website as our footer
all right now sometimes you may have
more than one header and footer so it's
a good idea to give these an ID or a
class so in this case I'm going to give
it an ID of just main header okay the
same thing with the footer down here
we'll give that an ID of main footer
because some people might actually use
for instance that the title of a blog
post the title and date and stuff they
might wrap that inside of a header it
doesn't necessarily mean it has to be
your your your main website header okay
now I really don't want to get into CSS
in this video but I will add just a
couple simple styles to the header all
right now when you're adding CSS usually
you want to put in an external file but
you can put it up in the in the head
area inside of a style tag okay and you
can let it know that this is going to be
CSS this is not required the type you
don't have to have this but sublime
actually puts it by default and then in
here let's say we want to grab on to the
ID of main header so when ideas
represent is represented with a number
sign okay so we'll say id main - header
I'm not going over this thoroughly
because we will do this in the next
video but for the main header let's say
we want
we want to align the text to the center
let's say we want to add a background
color of black okay since the background
is black let's change the text color
which is just going to be color and
we'll change that to white and then I'm
just going to add a little bit of
padding around everything so we'll say
10 pixels so I'll save that reload and
now we have a little website header all
right we want to grab on to the footer
remember we gave it an ID of main footer
and all I'm going to do with that is
just text aligned to the center and
we'll just make the font size a little
bigger all right don't worry about
learning these styles yet we're going to
go over all of this in the next video so
let's save it reload and now our footer
is centered all right the last thing I'm
going to go over is the meta tags that
you can use in your head area okay so
when Google indexes your website or your
webpages it's going to look at the
description and it's going to look at
your keywords things like that so let's
go right under the title here and let's
put in a meta tag now meta tags are
going to have a name attribute so we're
going to say this is the description of
our page and then it's going to have a
Content attribute which will be the
actual content so let's just say awesome
blog by traversing media okay so that's
our description and then we can also add
keywords so that would be another meta
tag with the name of keywords okay it's
going to have content and the content is
going to be a comma separated list so
we'll say web design web design blog web
dev blog you might put your company name
stuff like that alright and if we save
that there's not going to be any
difference from here if we look at the
source code control you you'll see that
now that stuff is added here and Google
will actually look at that stuff when it
scans your web site so the last thing I
want to do is just link the two pages
together
teach eat and the blog area so what I'll
do is put a link in the blog page see
we'll go right under the header here and
we'll just put to put an a tag and
that's going to go to index.html and
let's just say go to index all right so
if we reload we have this go to index I
click that that'll bring us here now
let's go to index.html and we'll go to
the very top right under the body and
let's put an a tag and we'll say go to
blog dot HTML and the text will say go
to blog and then let's just put an HR
underneath ok reload and now we can
switch back and forth to our pages and
that's how navigation is put together
alright guys so I think we're going to
stop here all that all this markup will
be in the description
allow the link to download the zip file
hopefully you learned something from
this and you enjoyed it like I said at
the beginning of the video of yours if
you're a subscriber of mine you probably
already know all this stuff if you if
you've watched the whole thing that's
awesome thanks for that and that's it
please subscribe if you like this I do
you know much more advanced stuff so
you'll learn much more and leave it a
like if you liked it if you didn't like
it go ahead and leave it a dislike and I
will see you in the next video