alright guys in this video I want to
talk to you about return values so the
first couple functions that we made what
they did is they either just printed
something out immediately or they made
like a simple calculation and print it
out the answer real quick however there
are certain times where we're going to
want to function to do something like
make the calculation and we're not going
to want to print it out right then and
there what we're going to want to do is
actually store the answer or the
response so we can use it later in our
program so how would we um take like the
answer or the result and save it in a
variable to use later well for that we
need something called a return statement
and it returns of course a return value
so for this example what I want to do is
I do this in all my program tutorials
I'm going to show you guys a cool little
function and it calculates the age of
girls that you're allowed to date so for
example I could not date a 13 year old I
can only date someone who is you know
the appropriate age for me I'm 27 so I
don't know it's like it's 20 an
appropriate age is like 23 I know like
25 is so there's actually a formula for
this I'm going to be teaching it so
aloud dating age is what the name is and
of course the piece of information that
needs is my age so after this what we're
going to be doing is we're going to be
calculating the girls age that I'm able
to date the limit so the formula for
this is whatever your age is so my age
which would be 27 in my case divide that
by two and add seven so in your head
take your age / 2 in add seven that's
the age of girls you're allowed to date
no younger than that or it's creepy so
of course this is the equation however
we just don't want to print it out right
now what we're going to be doing is
we're going to be taking this value and
storing in variable
so that we can use it later on so in
order to do that we need a new keyword
it's called a return and it says what do
you want back from this calculation what
answer do you want back well in this
case just the girls age so of course now
we can use this as well just like we did
before so you know before and that's not
what I wanted we can call hold on a
second my ear is a chin
well it's tit and I'm ready to move on
okay so we'll say that a loud dating age
is 27 because it takes your age now if
we just run this program right here
nothing prints out on the screen because
this entire statement is equal to the
return value and what is it I don't know
so now that this is equal to some number
of a girl's age what I want to do is
take that and store in a variable so
Bucky's limit is equal to some number
now so now I can do something like print
Bucky can date mmm I'll just do this
date girls
Bucky's limits or older so now I can
print this bad boy out and check it out
so my limit is I can date girls that are
20 and a half or older so hopefully I
get one that's twenty and a half because
you know then she can like drive me
around bars if you can't even drink so
that was pretty so much thing to say you
have to edit that out but seriously if
any girls are out there give me a call
all right anyways moving on so say that
we wanted to do this for someone else
well okay that was like the longest
delay between copying and pasting all
right so say that we wanted to do it for
my friend in my free
is 49 years old actually don't have
friend is 49 years old actually don't
have any friends at all alright and his
name is creepy Joe yeah I got a friend
named creepy Joe who freakin cares so if
we take this copy and paste it as well
save us some time so creepy Joe let's
see what his limit is our a so my limit
and anyone who's 27 out there do not
take girls younger than 20 and a half
and if you're 49 years old your limit
would be 31 and a half so again not only
in this tutorial did we learn about
return values but we also learn an
awesome equation so you can figure out
okay how young of a girl can I date
because I know all you guys out there
were wondering it so I actually run this
calculation and tell me your limit on
the forum because I'm actually quite
interested to know and also another cool
thing that you can do and if anyone
wants to do this for like a mini forum
challenge um go through a list of will
say age is like 15 to 60 and print the
person's age the dude's age and their
limit right next to each other side by
side one row at a time so that would be
a pretty cool table so if anyone wants
to do that post the core of my code on
my forum but for now thank guys for
watching don't forget subscribe and that
we'll see you later