alright guys in this video we're going
to be learning about a range not like a
range like home home on the range
not that one I'm talking about a range
of numbers so this is also a cool way
that we can create a loop without a list
and if you're scratching your head and
you're like okay well what the heck are
we going to loop through event well
that's when we're going to teach you
guys so make a for loop and then name
the variable anything you want I'll just
name my necks and usually we said
something like enlist and then you wrote
the list name but what if we just said
okay
we don't have anything to loop through
but I want to have this loop occur ten
times I want something to occur ten
times well what we can do is we can
write range and inside here ten what
this is pretty much saying is okay the
loop through this this is pretty much
the same thing as making a list really
quick so probably easier if we just see
so right now X is equivalent to the
numbers 0 through 9
since remember computers start counting
at ten now you can actually do anything
ten times it doesn't even need to
involve X so if you just did this I
printed out Bucky is awesome ten times
there's actually a really good program
for people with a you know self
confidence issues Bucky's awesome look
ease look you know what I am awesome all
right so enough of that
and let me actually go back to X because
I want to show you guys some other
things and another thing whenever you
want to clear out your console because I
don't know maybe it's just annoying just
hit this little trash bucket button
there mazuma stupid trash man who won't
take my freaking cardboard but anyways
just minimize that all right so back up
to here so of course whenever we print
this out X is equivalent to the numbers
zero through nine now we can also do
something out
and that's this instead of just writing
ten right there we can actually give a
range of numbers so by default it starts
at zero now let's say that we wanted to
start XM five and we wanted it to go to
I don't know I have a maximum of like
twelve or something who knows oh really
now I got the hiccups okay it's going to
tick me off
all right so press run and check it out
so now it starts at five and it loops
all the way until it gets to 12 so when
we don't have two numbers then it starts
at zero implicitly when we have two
numbers we have a beginning and the end
now the last thing is what happens when
we do this with three numbers you might
be thinking beginning middle end well
not exactly the first one is what number
do you want to start at the second one
is where you want to end that and the
third one is your increment so this
means count from 10 to 40 but do it in
steps of 5 so 10 15 20 tomato tomahto
so on and so forth so pretty freakin
sweet
so again if you ever want to specify by
how much how much why can I not talk
today how much you want to count by this
is how you do that
now I guess I have time in this video to
show you guys about um the only other
loop I want to talk to you about right
now and this is called a while loop now
the while loop is a special loop that
loops as long as a condition is true so
you don't explicitly give it either a
list you don't give it a range of
numbers you just said ok just keep
looping until this one test equals false
so let me show you quick quick example
make a variable called buttcrack
if you don't name it but correct your
program is not going to work I'm just
getting flow now what we do is we use
the keyword while and after this we give
a simple test
so if buttcrack is less than 10
and just do something we'll just print
out buck crack now of course
oops did I accidently say butt crack
then I write my name
Bucky crack alright so anyways what's
going to happen in this case is this
well five is always going to be less
than ten you know unless in the middle
of our program math and physics suddenly
decided change so if we just run this
right now as you can see it keeps
printing out five five five five five
forever so what we need to do and clear
this out so what we need to do is we
need a way to change the value of
buttcrack to increase on every single
iteration of the loop so if you're right
buck crack plus equals one what this
line of code right here does is it adds
one two but crack every time so the
first time this loop occurs it's going
to print out five and then add one two
butt crack so the next time the loop
occurs after that butt crack is now
equal to six and it does this as you can
see all the way until this variable butt
crack equals 10 is 10 less than 10 well
no it's not so since this is false
that's when your program knows to stop
the loop so again that's a while loop
and for the test you need a way to
change the variable in here so um if it
just if you never change it and it keeps
running over and over and over again
this is called an infinite loop and it's
not very good from your for your
computer because it could actually crash
your computer so don't do that so again
we learn about range we learn about
while loop and I accidentally wrote
Bucky and set a butt crack so hope you
enjoy see you next time