shuts up us welcome to another video
where I am going to be teaching you some
really cool things that you can do with
shrinks the first thing is how to access
individual characters from a string so
say that we had a user sign up for the
site and their name was tuna Mick fish
which was actually the name of my great
uncle tournament fish and the first
thing I want to mention is this whatever
people count like whenever you teach
like a kid to count they always start at
1 1 2 3 4 however computers are
different computers start counting is
zero so just keep that in mind because
it's going to come into play right now
so in order to access an individual
character from this name or from a
string type the variables name which is
user and in between square brackets
write the position of the character you
want to get so if you want to get the
first character you don't type one you
actually type zero since computers start
counting is zero so again it outputs T
so this is zero this is position 1 2 3 4
5 so let's see the 5 should be the M and
indeed it is so pretty cool now another
thing I want to mention is this so
computers start counting is zero and
then go from left to right you can also
go from right to left now if you ever
want the last character what you can do
is press negative 1 now it's not
negative 0 like you might think because
negative 0 is 0 so negative 1 is always
the last character which is in this case
H so you can also do that for not only
last one but say you want to start at
the end and put negative 1 negative 2
negative 3 is the I so on and so forth
so that is how you access individual
characters from a string again the
variable name and the position in square
brackets now another thing that you can
do is you can actually slice out a
section of the name
so in order to do that I'll show you
guys what I'm talking about it's really
easy if you just look at it you write
two numbers the first one is where you
want to start so say we wanted to start
it
zero one two which is the end and the
last one is where you want to stop
so we'll say okay this M is five so stop
at this F which is seven now whenever we
hit enter it gives us this little
section right here and you see it didn't
include that F because it stops right
before it's pretty much saying okay um
when you get to this character stop so
that's how you slice out um some
characters from a middle of a string now
I want to mention one more thing
actually two more things so you use the
little colon right here to say where you
want to stop into where you want to
start and stop so I might say now if you
ever forget to include or if you ever
just don't include the beginning then it
automatically assumes that you want to
start from the very beginning so this
pretty much means start at the beginning
and go to the seventh position and just
like that you can also forget that
stopping point and it will go all the
way to the end so again that just gets
this right there now if you do with both
of them then of course it'll start at
the beginning and stuff at the end which
pretty much gives you um what you
started with the whole entire thing
pretty simple and actually since we have
time I'll show you guys one other cool
function you know how I said that
whenever we write actual program we're
going to be using these things called
functions you know we learned one had
print stuff out on the screen
simple enough well another thing I want
to tell you is quite often you're want
to get the length of a string so say we
have this name right here but we don't
know how long it is how many characters
are in it well the function that we can
use for this is L e n and what this does
is in between its parenthesis you can
type in any string just type in some
random characters and
enter and it'll say how many characters
are in that string so if you ever want
to know how many characters are in the
word deflect is cast if it's 21 now of
course just like basic strings you can
use variables as well so if we do this
it's pretty much just going to say what
is the length of to Namak fish anyone
want to take guests before I hit enter
if you guess 11 you were correct and of
course this counts 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
so this blank space counts is a
character as well just something that
you may want to remember so that is it
and the only other thing I want to
mention is if you ever have questions
about my tutorials if you ever have any
code that's not working or if you just
want the source code for my tutorials if
you go to my website
Bucky's room to org slash forum I'm
going to put all the source code in the
Python section so click this again
here's the source code for my last
tutorial and you can just copy it and
use it if you ever your view so again if
you have any questions ask me there
thank you guys for watching and well
I'll see you later