alright guys welcome back in this video
I'm going to talk to you about two key
words
the first one is break and the second
one is continue and these are actually
some cool keywords that we can put
inside a loop to make the loop do some
cool things so for this example we're
going to be building a very basic game
magic number and set the number equal to
anything from 0 to 100 I'm going to set
mine equal to 26 so we'll say that the
computer gave us this magic number we
didn't know what it was let's just
pretend that we can't obviously see that
it's 26 all right now but we'll say it
gave us a number and we have to build a
loop to run through the numbers once 100
and see if our number equals the magic
number pretty much find the magic number
so we decide to first build a loop so
we're going to make a loop tree each
number is n and since we're looping
through 100 numbers we want to stop at
101 this is going to give us 0 to 100 so
pretty much we're going to loop through
this and n is going to be something from
0 to 100 well now we want to test if n
is the magic number so we make an if
statement inside the loop so if n is
magic number then that means that we
found the magic number so what do we
want to do whenever we actually find the
magic number well we can just print out
print and I want to show you guys
something real quick so this doesn't
confuse you and don't mind what I'm
doing with these little quotes right now
basically I'll tell you guys all right
so let me show you
Oh correct I keep like thinking of more
except to tell you so right now
your computer is going to read every
single line every single line of code
and it's going to execute it
right here it's going to set a variable
equal to some number so on and so forth
however sometimes you're going to want
to add little notes in your code and
these are just notes for developers and
people to read just like um you know
little notes that you want the computer
to ignore and not execute but you need
to have just so other developers and
your co-workers can understand your code
this is called a comment now whenever
you make a comment on a single line um
you can just write amp or hashtag the
thing above the three and write any
comment you want like okay this program
finds a magic number so now we can
execute this program and you'll never
read up whenever we do whenever it gets
to this comment it's pretty much going
to skip over it so again it's a way of
adding a line of code for people that
your computer skips over now this
hashtag right here or number sign is
only for one line now I want to show you
guys another example so what I want to
do is I want to ignore all of these
lines so what I can do is I can add a
hashtag at the beginning of every one
but whenever we have a bunch of lines of
code it can get kind of confusing so if
you want to add a multi-line comment put
three little single quotes where it
starts and three little single quotes
where it ends so again this is just
because I wrote a piece of code and um I
go oh yeah I got to teach you something
else
so I don't want to run this yet so now
whenever I run this what our computer
does is it basically just runs this line
and ignores everything else so again
that's your little mini tutorial on
comments now here's the thing I wanted
to teach you you know how I told you
guys that you can pretty much add
together numbers like 5 plus 4
print out the answer and you can also
add together strings like Bucky +
Roberts and whenever you add together
strings
it's called concatenating a string it
pretty much um takes two strings and
puts them together
well what if you wanted to do something
like this
Bucky plus for some reason you wanted to
write Bucky 9 instead of Bucky Roberts
well whenever we try to run this check
out what's going to happen we're going
to get an error and that's because it
says ok whenever I add strings together
just stick them together in a one big
string whenever I add numbers together
just use math but you're trying to add a
string with a number so what the heck
and I was supposed to do you're kind of
confusing me that's why it gives us the
error so now I want to show you guys
something else whenever we want to print
out a number along with a string what we
need to do is this we need to separate
them with a comma instead of a plus sign
so plus is for only adding two things of
the same data type together if we ever
wanted to write nine Bucky or something
like that just write print nine just
like a number and then print Bucky just
as a string now whenever you run this it
prints nine Bucky so that's how we print
out numbers on the same line as strings
simple enough so why am I telling you
that
well because I was about to print out a
number on the same line is a string
obviously so what I want to do is again
we have to remember we have a magic
number and looping through all the
numbers 0 to 100 until we finally hit
the magic number so once we finally
found it print n which is a number
remember it's a variable but it's still
a number and then we'll print out
something like is the magic number
simple enough now what we can do is we
can just loop through this right now and
in the blink of eye what it did is it
loop through 0 1 3 3 4 5 6 7 until it
got to 26 and once it got to 26
if 26 is the magic number then print out
26 is the magic number
so now what I want to do is I want to
tell you guys about the break statement
and I'm actually going to finish writing
my code and then I'll talk you guys to
real one last time all right so as you
can see real quick what I did is I added
a few more lines to the code and the
first one is to display the brick
statement now what the break statement
or keyword does is it pretty much breaks
out or stops your loop now why did I
have this right here well whenever we
find the magic number which is 26
there's no need to continue looping
through all the other numbers we know
it's not 27 28 29 any of those so why
waste our computer's memory looping
through numbers that it doesn't matter
so it says okay whenever you find the
magic number print this out right here
and then break which pretty much means
stop the loop you can remember it
because it means break out of the loop
now this line of code right here is just
a display that it actually breaks out so
every other number aside from the magic
number such as 0 1 2 3 it's going to
print that out anyways and then once it
finds it it breaks out and stops
printing so you guys are going to see
what's going on so again it starts off
just printing every single number right
here because it test fits the magic
number well it wasn't so I'll just print
the number anyways and it does that all
the way until it gets to 26 now at 26
and does equal the magic number so print
n is the magic number and then break so
that's why it doesn't print out 27 28 29
30 because what we did is we broke out
of the loop which
much means says okay you can stop the
loop now no need to waste your memory or
your resources on anything else we
already found the answer so again I know
this was a tutorial was a little longer
than expected but now we know about
comments now we know how to use the
break statement and we even learned how
to add a decision inside of a loop how
cool is that
so in the blink of an eye your computer
can make like 8,000 decisions a lot
faster than you know having to do it by
hand so I hope you enjoy I hope you
learned at least a little something
thank you for watching don't forget
subscribe and also actually I'm not
going to let you go yet your homework
assignment or your challenge I'll call
it that is this make a program to loop
through the numbers 1 to 100 and print
out any number that is a multiple of 4
so for a 12 16 so on and so forth but do
it programmatically now I'll give you
guys a nice little key word if you take
a number and divide it by 4 and what you
have left is 0 again remember the
modulus sign is the remainder so
whenever you run this little statement
right here the numbers that you divide
by 4 and have a remainder of 0 are the
numbers that are divisible by 4 simple
enough so if anyone can do that and I
will be incredibly impressed but for now
that's your homework assignment and once
it's complete post down my forum and
then you're ready to move on to the next
video so I'll see you there