alright guys welcome back to another
video and you probably notice that the
sound on this video is a little bit
different and also my computer screen is
slightly different and that's because
I'm on my laptop right now and the
reason that I'm filming this on my
laptop is because we're going to
download a new piece of software in this
tutorial and I already have it installed
on my other computer so I didn't want to
install it again and mess everything up
but what we're going to be installing is
called a Python IDE it's a last piece of
software that we need to install because
this little program right here it's
really good for learning basic commands
and testing stuff out or whenever we
want to make an actual Python program
it's good to work with a bunch of files
and you know just use something a little
more advanced so well I'm going to be
showing you guys how to install is this
played on IDE now it doesn't matter what
IDE you choose but this is my favorite
it's called pipe looks a bit low I feel
like I'm gonna puke what if I just start
puking in the middle of this video that
would be hilarious but nonetheless
choose any IDE you want I'm going to be
using PyCharm
and in order to get this this is the
website right here JetBrains comm slash
PyCharm and my laptop is in the living
room so I can hear people driving by all
the time anyways go ahead and click get
pycharm and I actually have the
professional Edition because I don't
know I just um use it all the time but
if you click download then what it's
going to do just like before is it's
going to give you downloads this file
right here now double click this and
let's see if I remember how to install
it yes you can have permission next I
agree next and might as well create a
shortcut pretty much stick with all of
the defaults also if you ever want to
change anything then you can just change
it in the program but for now just stick
with defaults
there's like a guy I don't know if he's
weed eating or mowing or sounds like
he's using a huge electric toothbrush
but whatever r-right so finish that and
now you can close this out let the clean
everything up
see you later window and double click it
and see what we got now okay what's this
say you can import sentence for in
previous version and nope this is my
first time installing so just click OK
and of course um if you don't have a
license key yet
then you just have a 30 day free trial
trial but so again I don't have a
license key not for this computer I
actually have one for my other computer
don't know if I could use it for this
one and of course if you have a license
key if you bought the full version then
you can enter it here however we can
just choose evaluate free for 30 days to
see if we like this IDE first we read
this real quick ok I read it I read it
trust me alright now this baby can load
up and it says a couple things that we
have to start with keymap ID let's see
this is just a theme which is pretty
much a colors
I actually like um dark yellow this is
the one that I use and ok so this is
pretty much just a highlighting or
syntax and I'm going to be using this
first so hopefully it shows up good in
my videos if not have to switch some
from something else
yep alright so just pretty much says
whenever you pick a new theme you have
to restart it and that's what's
happening right now so now once you got
your theme you see everything is cool
and dark now pretty sweet alright so in
order to start using this IDE of course
you need to create a new project in a
project is pretty much where all of your
files are stored so the project name for
this is just going to be like um I'm at
YouTube and whenever you type in your
project name it automatically fills in
the location right here so don't change
them like manually and the project type
it can just be an empty project for now
and everything else is good
whenever you download this IDE it
automatically finds your interpreter
which is pretty much on Python the very
first thing we downloaded in the first
video so that's what this is choosing
right now so it's pretty cool how it's
you know it sets everything up for you
and of course this is okay windows and
actually don't like these tips even
though they're helpful so close out that
and now check it out we now have a
pretty cool IDE but where the heck is
our you know we're ahead company type
stuff in well if you expand this right
here it's going to show all your files
and we don't have any files yet so what
we need to do is right-click our project
name mine's YouTube and we're going to
write new Python file so our project can
have a bunch of different files you can
even have like um text files in it
images if we're working with images but
for right now let's create a basic um
Python file and I'm just going to name
this um first name it anything you want
and also the extension for Python files
are dot py so make sure you have Python
file selected and also name it dot P why
why not what was that noise you know
another thing I live next to a fire
station so all the time this stupid uh
fire alarms gone off so it's really
annoying but anyways back to the sort
what oh yeah right now I'm here in the
Train
I hate making videos in my living room
alright so delete anything out of your
Python file and let's just run a simple
command let's just print something out
so print we already know how to use this
in here put a string like I hope this
works and now in order to run this as
you can see whenever you're making a an
actual program you just can't hit enter
and it runs like you're on your show so
what you need to do for the first time
is right click it and hit run first and
get out of the way now all of your
results are going to pop up in this
little command window down here so
whenever you change something else like
I love
and hit run your new results are going
to pop up down here so that way you can
work on all your stuff up here your
files are on the left and the results
are on the bottom now whenever you run
it for the first time you do have to
right click it and hit run but any time
after that you can just click this
button or hit shift f10 but I just click
this button it's a little bit easier and
that runs your entire on project so now
that you have a suite IDE we can now
actually start making some cool programs
so thank you guys for watching don't
forget to subscribe and I'll see you
guys in the next video