alright guys welcome back and in this
video I want to talk to you about lists
one of the most important and also one
of the things in Python that you're
going to be using a lot so a list is
pretty much exactly um what you think it
is just like a list of numbers you can
actually have a list of anything but in
this video I'm going to be showing you
guys just a list of numbers because
that's the easiest type of list of work
with so I'm going to name my list
players so say that I'm a coach and I
want to keep track of all my players on
a certain team so set a variable equal
to something and instead of just having
a list the numbers like this you
actually need to pull all of your items
in between square brackets that's how
Python knows that okay I'm working with
a list so I have one player name 29
another name 58 another they say name 66
another with the number 66 100 wears
that jersey 71 and my last player is
number 87 and these are actually numbers
from my favorite sports team so if
anyone can tell what my favorite sports
team is just by the number jersey they
wear then I will actually be impressed
so anyways for those who don't care
about that right now we have a list of
numbers of course remember in computer
programming and Python it always starts
counting at 0 so this is position 0 1 2
etc etc now just like a string what we
can do is type the name of the list and
then the position number and it can get
that item so again 0 1 2 so players at
position 2 that be 66 alright simple
enough so let's figure out how to do
something else so that is how we access
an item in that position but we can also
change it to a new value so we'll say ok
actually we traded number 66 to another
team and instead we got 68 so what this
does is say ok set players to 268 just
like we do variables
so now whenever we talk about players as
you can see 66 which was the old value
is now changed to 68 so again this is
how you just rigged it information and
this is how you set equal to new values
or new numbers now another thing that we
can do is add more items to the end of
this list and we can do it in one of two
ways the first way is just to save
players which is equal to this list and
we can add it with another list let's
say I don't know 90 91 in like 98 now
whenever we hit enter it gives us our
new list which is the old one of this
one plus what we just wrote however this
doesn't permanently change the players
list the original players list is still
the same it just temporarily
um gives you a new list so what you
could actually do is you can actually
set this entire statement equal to a new
arm variable like players like new
players or something and use that
variable but just remember that this
statement itself doesn't change this
original list now there are actually
going to be some times where we do want
to change the lists permanently and add
items on there that is going to affect
um the list itself so in order to add
items permanently freaking caps lock we
can do players dot and call the function
append now I know I didn't talk to you
guys much about functions or the dot
operator but I just want to show you
guys this real simple trick so what this
does is it basically says this write the
name of your list then right after it
without any spaces right the dot and
this means do something to this list now
append pretty much means add something
on so in between here we write the
number that we want to add on like I
don't know 120 so now in this line we
added another item or number on to this
list and if we print that bad boy out
check it out this was our list before
and now here is our new
list so again append permanently changes
your list the plus sign temporarily
changes it alright not bad not bad lists
are pretty friggin cool so far now
another thing I want to talk to you guys
about is how to slice items from the
list just like we did with our strings
so if we ever want to do players - what
this does is it starts at the beginning
which is right here and it goes to
position 2 so 0 1 2 and of course
remember that it doesn't actually
include this item it just says ok that's
the stopping point so as you can see
just like slicing characters you can
also do it with arm lists I can't even
talk right now
I think my brains about to explode ok
so aside from that we saw that you can
just use this to display now you can
also use this to set it equal to new
values at once
so before you see up here how we took
one item from the list and set it equal
to a new value well since this piece of
code right here returns two items we can
set this equal to two new items such as
I don't know let's make something easy
to see so let's this say is it says okay
take the items at position 1 0 & 1 and
set them equal to 0 and 0 respectively
so that is how you replace multiple
items or multiple values at once all
right not bad now another thing that you
can do is this and this is actually
really handy say that instead of 0 0
which are actual numbers then we just
wanted to remove those items so what we
can do is this if we take the first two
items from the list and set them equal
to empty square brackets with no values
in them it's going to say ok pretty much
take these values in and remove them or
set them to empty not even zero so now
whenever we type players check it out
these values which were 0 are now
permanently gone so that's how you
delete
from your list now what if you just
wanted to delete your entire list well
it may sound confusing but it's actually
pretty easy take players and set it
equal to empty now remember by default
this colon right here says where do you
want to stop and where do you want to
start or certain stop well if we just
have a colon - enough at the left and
nothing to the right it's going to grab
the entire list and of course we know
setting equal to square brackets says
take this entire list and empty
everything so now whenever you're right
players we just get an empty list so
that's how you clear an entire list by
removing all the items and again I know
this is a lot to cover we list but we
are going to be using lists a lot it's
kind of intuitive but it's kind of
confusing at first so you might have to
watch this tutorial one more time if you
have any questions at all then just ask
me I'm gonna forum I'll be happy to
answer it for you
but for now thank guys for watching and
I'll see you guys in the next video