alright guys welcome back to another
video and you know how in the last
Oriels i showed you guys how to make a
basic function and I also told you guys
that inside your parentheses you could
have extra variables which are pretty
much extra information that your
function needs in order to work now
the technical name for this extra
information is an argument so if you
have more than one variables there
called arguments and I'm going to show
you guys how to have a default value for
your arguments in this video if you guys
are really okay why would we ever need
this it's useless
well let me give you guys an example say
that we're using Python for web
development and we're making a social
network and whenever the user signs up
they can select if they're male or
female and then it'll display on their
profile however if they enter nothing
then we don't just want to enter an
empty value into our database or else
bad things can happen get some
unexpected results so we want to set a
default value further gender so let's
make a function called get gender and
we'll set the sex and instead of just
passing it in a value explicitly we'll
say okay
by default sex is equal to unknown so
that way we can have something to put in
our database instead of just emptiness
avoid so now what we can do is say okay
if sex
if they enter M then we'll just set
equal to male so again this the final
variable will be the one that we throw
into our database and then we'll just
put else if sex is female
then set equal to the word female
and of course the last thing we want to
do is print sex which would be pretty
much printing it to our database instead
just on the screen but for this example
it'll work fine so now what we can do is
this
actually if I type all these examples is
probably going to be really easy to see
what's going on all right let me adjust
my chair a Justin - Justin it's what
they called me and I don't know I was
trying to think of some funny say but
something like with a name Justin but I
don't know if anyone has anything good
then let me know and I'll use it in like
10 tutorial never won't forget that it
forgets that I couldn't come up with
anything all right so let's run this and
check out what happens so if they
entered em it says okay by default we
have sex equal to unknown but you
entered em so we're going to use that
value instead so if they enter F okay we
say okay sex you want to equal F now in
this one right here we didn't enter
anything we didn't enter em F or any
letters at all so in this case it would
say okay since you didn't give me a
value to set sex equal to I'm going to
enter it as unknown by default so again
that is the default value so now sex is
equal to unknown so when it prints it
out to your database it just prints out
unknown so it's a lot better than just
printing out nothing because again like
I say it could confuse the database and
there are other examples when this is
useful as well but hopefully you guys
understand what a default value is
basically if you forget to set the
variable explicitly it has something to
store by default so think guys for
watching don't forget to subscribe and
again tell me a Justin joke if you have
one so see you later