alright guys in this video I want to
talk to you about variable scope because
whenever a lot of people are starting
out with Python functions specifically
they have a little trouble understanding
what variables you're allowed to use
where so I'm going to show you guys the
very basic rules of variable scope it's
going to be really easy and save you
guys a lot of trouble so let's make a
simple variable called a and set it
equal to I don't know any number you
want it set equal to anything you want
number string who cares so now I want to
show you guys two functions you pretty
much have to make any two functions you
want I'll just name one corn and they're
going to do the same exact thing they're
going to print a so print out a number
and make another function called fudge
again the functions name or the function
names don't really matter and this is
going to print a as well now below them
let's call both of them so corn and
fudge alright so pretty simple program
right now and whenever you run it we can
see they both print out the number they
both work properly so the first rule of
what variables your functions are
allowed to use is this if the variable
is created outside the function and
above it your function can access that
variable so this can access a and this
can also access a now why I'm even
making this tutorial is because of this
issue say that this variable was created
inside corn let me tighten it up a bit
so now we already see that we have an
error right here to set unresolved
reference and actually if we try to run
this we get this little error message
right here so the other row I want to
say is whenever a variable is created
inside a function only that function
that created it can access it so again
since this a variable was created inside
ORN only corn can use it so if it was
outside any one of them could use it but
since it was created inside corn this
variable now belongs to corn and corn is
pretty selfish because it doesn't let
any other functions use it so again that
is why we get this error right here and
whenever you run it we see it prints
this number out so corn prints that I'll
find but fudge does not so that is the
really simple Tumen explanation of
variable scope and well hopefully you
guys understand very basic rules I know
that this uh let me think there's
something else I could teach you real
quick all right oh I want to teach you
guys about like keyword arguments and
this thing called like um unknown amount
of arguments but it's gonna take a
little while so I'll just save it for
the next video but anyways thanks for
watching see you next time