alright guys in this video what I want
to do is I want to show you how to build
a function that can take any amount of
arguments so before what we did is we
built a function and will say that it
was adding two numbers together well we
can have it add like one number two
numbers however that can get kind of
cumbersome and say that we're making I
don't know like a calculator well we
don't know if the users going to try to
add two numbers or a hundred numbers or
a thousand numbers together so we don't
know how many arguments to have until
now we can X actually have a flexible
amount of arguments by adding the
Asterix sign and then the keyword which
is pretty much just like a normal
variable like before so what the Asterix
does right here is it's pretty much
saying we're going to be taking a bunch
of arguments but we don't know how many
yet so store them in this variable
however many they are so then we can
loop through them and another thing I
want to point out you're going to see
this args keyword a lot and you can
actually name this anything you want you
can name it tuna for you know your
program doesn't care however the reason
that you see this a lot is just because
it's common practice among Python
programmers to always name the flexible
argument parameter um args so again it
doesn't have to be named that even
though you're going to be seeing it so
now we have either one number or one
hundred numbers however many stored in
args so since we made a function called
add numbers probably should start adding
some numbers together so alright my my
Wow
all right it was a really hot in my
computer room so I opened my door like
slightly but since it's like cold
outside my room and warm inside I guess
there's a draft that keeps moving it
back and forward and it in middle my
tutorials it just like creaks and let's
see it's 3:40 9:00 a.m. right now so
it's pitch black so it's kind of
freaking me out anyways
nice little side story cool story bro
right alright so now we can just loop
through it like we would a normal four
loop so for a and args pretty much loop
through every single argument and do
something with it well we just want to
take a which is whatever value and add
it to the total so now we get a running
tally of the sum stored in the total
variable and we can just print out the
total right there so now we can just do
it for we can even do for one number
like three and it just adds three two oh
great now I got the freaking hiccups so
then just adds three to total and we can
do it for two numbers such as three and
thirty-two and we can even do it for
it's well that's not a number four
that's whatever the heck this is so
again one number two however many you
want it works the same regardless so
again how awesome is that instead of
having to write you know a bajillion
parameters pretty friggin sweet if you
ask me so that is how you use a function
with a flexible amount of arguments so
thank you guys for watching don't forget
to subscribe and I will see you in the
next tutorial