hey guys welcome back to our course
we're now on second episode which is
where we look at the asset folder
require a lot now I say asset folder but
it's actually called the project window
as well so let me just have a look down
here this is what we call the project
window if you right-click in the middle
of it and you do a show and Explorer
you're gonna end up in your actual
project folder so let me just step back
this is where we decided to save our
folder when we first made our project
right so this is our project folder if
we just click on it there is going to be
four folders well actually there's three
of those but temporary is only there
when the engine is booted with your
project opens so right now unit is open
this is why I have a temp folder now one
of these folder is actually called the
asset folder and what you're going to
realize when I click on it and I just
move it on this side is that it is a
reflection of the project window you see
on unity now if I just go up here
I'm on the Windows Explorer on the left
side here if I just right click create a
new say 8x I call it say Dave and I just
save if I go in my engine as you can
tell my text asset is there so I have
the scene which we save in the last
episode and I also have this text file
if I double click on it it opens it in
my default text editor
in this case that is Visual Studio so if
I just say hello world I close it now my
file called Dave dot txt should actually
contain elwell which we can see through
the inspector but we can also see by
going back instead of the asset folder
double clicking on that and in the
notepad as you can tell it says hello
world and if I just write something here
I'll say hi back
save this it's also going to be
reflected in here as well so as you can
tell they are the very very same thing
if I'm just playing with stuff in the
asset folder here I delete Dave it's
also going to be deleted from this
window same thing goes here so if you
were just to create say a c-sharp script
create it you go in your asset folder
and here it is a new behavior script
now if I delete it inside of the project
folder this is in action you cannot undo
so you gotta be really careful about
that if you delete stuff from the asset
folder
through the project window it's gonna be
deleted for real and it's gonna be
ending up in your recycle bin so gonna
be really careful about that you can
also restore them if you wish we're
gonna going to restore both of them and
as you can tell it is just going to be
import so now that we understand that
the asset folder slash project window is
just the same thing then we can start
importing some asset now when I say
asset I'm talking about
texture I'm talking about models I'm
talking about material fonts all that
kind of good stuff is what we call it an
asset and that is what your game is made
off in the end so let's just give it a
try right here I'm going to create a new
asset let's start by a folder actually
just a normal folder that I will call
artwork I'll also create another folder
called scene and what else let's go
ahead and create one more folder that
we're going to call script now I have
three folders what I want to do with
those is just pull them all in the root
asset folder so I'll simply drag and
drop like this and now they're all in
different folders right so I'll take my
game scene which we created in the last
episode and drag and drop it inside of
my scene folder all of that as always
being reflected directly inside of the
asset folder in the Windows Explorer
let's actually talk about importing some
actual asset now so if you're an artist
making some texture in Photoshop what
you're gonna end up doing at the very
end is uh saving your file as a PNG as a
Targa file as a JPEG you're not gonna be
saving it as a PSD file because that
doesn't work in unity yet but still
let's just assume that I've made a
texture I'm going to find texture really
quickly on my computer say a PSD here
called animation Fox right let's open it
in Photoshop and I'm simply going to
save this save as PNG file going to put
that on my death
stop why not and now here is how you
import it is very very simple already
have to do is drag and drop it inside of
your project folder so you could be
going from here drag and drop this in my
project window slash asset folder and
now it's part of this you can also do
something else with it you can also do
it via the asset window so say if unity
is not even open so we're gonna close
that I can still find my project folder
which is under pretty much where you
saved it in my case snake tutorial you
can simply go here and drag it so now
you really do understand that those are
the same exact thing if we just open it
up really quickly and instead of my
project there is d texture are important
now this was a quick example we're not
gonna be using this image because it
doesn't really make sense in our case
since we don't really have foxes but
just to show you just a quick mechanic
how this works I've grabbed this picture
of a box just a simple side of a box on
Google and we're gonna be looking at
what happens when we put it as a
material for our boxes so box texture I
rename it here and I drag and drop it
inside of my project folder I help me
name it in my project folder it doesn't
really it's the same thing so we have
this box texture we can also have like a
nice little preview on the right hand
side here what we can do at this point
is drag and drop this on top of an
object if we do that you're gonna see
your cursor is going to change but when
we drop it it creates a new folder and
it also applies the texture so the
folder it created is called materials
now materials are pretty much just a mix
of the texture you've decided to put on
your object and also what kind of
rendering technique need to be using so
in this case it's using a default welder
standard shader and it's using this
texture we put you can also change it
you have some different texture in
default when we first start unity you
have all of those by default but we're
gonna go back to our box texture now all
the little settings here you can
modify so you want to make it Melek you
want to make it more smooth you can play
with all that via the shader there is a
lot of stuff you can do here I'm just
going to let you play with that because
that is really like complicated stuff
and we're not really at that point just
yet but there is a lot of things to do
here now at this point if you want
outer-box to actually look like that you
can drag and drop the material on top of
them as well
so as you can tell we end up with four
little boxes here now I tend to put my
fixture inside the artwork folder and
also the material inside of the artwork
folder as well so everything that is art
related I just put that in the artwork
folder this is just something I do
personally you can just leave them
hanging in there if you want it's not
going to break any reference if you were
however to delete one of these you would
end up with like really pinkish material
so when you it is actually trying to
draw those boxes it's looking for which
technique it should use for drawing so
which rendering technique it should use
which shader and all that information is
contained within the material but now
the material is gone because we deleted
it so we end up with paint boxes which
just means that unity is telling you
that there is a problem and you need to
fix it now else you're gonna have that
in your game so we're just going to
create another material in another way
this time instead of just drag and
dropping like this like with it earlier
we're gonna be doing in a different way
we're gonna go up here create a just
material now you get to choose which
name you want to put it so I'm just
going to say box or box material that
could do the job or it simply box by
itself now the box material is what I'm
gonna be using to display all of those
four boxes here you can modify like the
color if you wish but we want this to
have a texture so over here on the
albedo click on box texture and you can
also just give it a small tin if you
wish as well okay so this cover is
pretty much as in normal texture in
material now let's talk about actual 3d
models so if you guy actually like go
inside of 3ds max Maya blender
the way you actually just get a model of
this is you do your modeling that's fine
but you actually export as the FBX now
FBX is a really common way to describe a
3d model and this is what most engines
use as a default unity is no different
if you just put the FBX inside of there
it's gonna convert it back in their own
format but you know it has no problem
reading in FBX is what I'm trying to say
now since the new update really really
it's also taking in blender file I don't
know for how long it's actually going to
take them but if just give it a try here
I have an object that just lays
somewhere in a folder here so let me
just go check right here happy low poly
wolf this is an actual blender file I'm
going to actually drag and drop this in
my new folder here in my asset folder
and as you can tell you can actually get
a preview down here this is a blender
file but it was able to actually convert
it to a unity model file so this is
really cool something really new now if
that doesn't work for you you're using a
older version of unity or it just
decided not to support the blender fall
anymore which can actually happen
because blender decide to change your
file format every now and then so if
that doesn't work go back in blender
export your model as an FBX you're a
hundred percent sure is going to work if
it's in the FBX and then what you can
actually do is once you have this here
this is an actual model so I'll take
that drag it in my artwork folder and if
I want to see it in my game I can simply
drag and drop it in my scene as you can
tell or drag and drop it in my are key
which is going to put it at zero zero
zero and you can play around with it
modify the scale have a lot of fun and
that is an actual model now when you
have a model like that when you import a
model you're usually also importing a
material from either blender to the S
max or Maya
so in blender I had three different
materials for this very muddled and they
were all important inside of the
material folder I had the one called
black the other one is called
on name and the other one is white so
just with this easy definition I'm just
assuming that the black is but you'll
call black as you can tell it has it in
here and the white is the white part of
the little low poly wolf if I change
those I'm actually going to change the
color of the wolf so I'm just directly
playing with the material I've imported
directly from blender so that is pretty
much what happens here and you can just
modify that now if I was to delete these
as you can tell I've deleted the unnamed
one name was actually what was on the
little sphere here if I delete white
they're gonna be rendered as pink and
I'm finally going to just pretty much
just delete everything and let me just
delete that wolf because I'm not going
to need it anymore same thing for the
box actually and we're just gonna go
back to having a clean folder which is
what we're aiming for in the end we're
trying to have this clean as clean as
possible because if it's clean then you
can actually work with it better right
there is a lot of other stuff you can
actually import you can import sound
file I didn't talk about that before so
let's just say that everything artistic
would be an asset and you just import it
the idea of the project window or the
asset folder now one last thing that is
actually an asset as well that I didn't
mention is the script a basic script
that you would write is also considered
as an asset so if you go right down here
and you do a create now you have the
option to create a c-sharp script or a
java script in our course here or like
on the whole channel I've never used
JavaScript I really do not like using
JavaScript for unity I'd rather use
c-sharp I think it's more powerful you
could get in like in the debate with me
but I don't really want to I don't want
to argue about this but every reference
I'm gonna be looking at everything gonna
be looking at online if it's a little
bit higher than just like noob stuff if
it's a little bit more advanced you're
gonna be seeing this in c-sharp this is
why I recommend that you learn c-sharp
and it's also I think something that is
gonna be quite useful for just
transition over to the other game engine
or transition over to other kind of
development if it's not web development
now if I just click on this
we create one let's just call it rotate
why not it creates a c-sharp script and
it just gives us some basic information
in it if we just open it really quickly
just to have a quick look now what we do
in this C sharp script is something
where to be talking about really soon
nothing in like two Episode but right
now we just we just need to understand
that we create a c-sharp script we do it
in the asset folder and that is pretty
much it we're gonna be leaving it here
for now and I simply put it inside of
our script folder this is something that
you need to realize is connected in your
Windows Explorer as well so if you were
to just wipe the asset folder on your
project if you were to just delete this
guy here you would also delete all of
your asset in your game so just be
really careful about that and I'm going
to be wrapping this up in the next
episode we're gonna be talking about
objects and their components so the
things on the right hand side here so
guys thanks for watching leave a like on
the video if you'd like to see more
courses if you'd like to just give me a
comment you can also do that in the
comment section down here and also check
out the patreon page if you wish and
support me subscribe to the channel and
I'll be seeing you in the next episode