hey guys welcome to our very first
course we have here on the n3k channel
it is going to be a course about unity
so everything you need to know about the
engine is going to be covered we're also
going to do an introduction to coding so
if you don't know how to code just yet
this is a very good place to start so at
the very beginning we're going to create
a project explore all the windows you
have in unity and then move on to coding
a little bit we're also going to have a
good look at the Unity engine namespace
which means that we're going to be
looking at function that unity gives us
and we're going to be able to just make
our lives so much easier with those and
also if you're new to coding I still
suggest that you stick around because
while you're going to be learning the
Unity engine but also that is how I
learned just by looking at somebody else
doing it copying it on my side and just
eventually just picking up the patterns
that is how I learned and I just
recommend that if you're new at least
try that because that might quite help
who knows on top of that so on top of
learning the unity engine and also
learning some function in the namespace
we're going to be building a game so if
you never really build a game this is
also going to be a very good experience
for you the game we're going to be
building is a simple snake game the
reason I chose a snake game is because
I'm able to cover a lot of coding
techniques in that symbol game so we're
going to be talking about
multi-dimensional arrays we're going to
be talking about getting inputs from the
keyboard talking about moving objects
all very simple topics but this is
pretty much something that is at the
base of a lot of games so we're gonna be
covering those topics and without
further ado let's actually just jump
right into it so when you're going to be
opening up unity for the very first time
this is a kind of window you're gonna be
having so basically it asks you to
create a project which is what we're
going to be doing right now so the
project name undermine snag tutorial or
unity course you can name this pretty
much anything you want now you're also
going to have a location down here this
is where your folder your asset for your
project folder is going to be put so
mine has its own location here I'm fine
with that I'm also going to be putting
this on 3d by default to put yours in 2d
the only real difference is that when
you boot the engine a lot of settings
are going to be set for you to work in
2d now those are real
easy to just reverse once we're inside
and I'm used actually working in 3d
since unity is actually it's just it's a
3d engine that's why it's called unity
3d I'm just more used to using it in 3d
even though we're going to be making a
2-d game here so going to be leaving
that on 3d create my project and we're
going to be looking at the interface
you're going to get now this is not
exactly how yours should look at the
moment and I will introduce you the very
first thing we'll be looking at at the
very top right here there is a little
layout button here little layout
drop-down menu now this is really
depending on which one you like the most
in the end if you want to follow this
tutorial at its full potential and you
know just have the windows where I put
my windows make sure you put yours on
tall this is what is going to end up
looking like and then we're going to be
moving some windows around so we can
have the same exact layout as I have now
if you already work with unity before
you pretty much already have your layout
so just suggest you stick with that just
stick with something that you're really
comfortable using so mine is something
like this I'm going to be playing with
the windows a little bit my inspector
read the video right
just going to make sure that it's all
the way here now the R key and the
project window same thing just going to
push them on the right-hand side the
next thing I tend to do is I take my
project folder over here I'll
right-click on it and I put that in a
one column layout that is how you unity
actually use the display things before
then they came out with the two column
layout which I don't really like it just
gives you a nice little search here
where you can just search for models
prefab or scripts we'll see more about
this a little bit later on but right now
I just make sure to leave it on one
column layout now when I actually do my
out I just use one more window on top of
that so I'm just going to select it
really quickly we're going to go to the
very top here find our console window
right here and I'm going to be grabbing
this by the little tab you see here
you'll be grabbing this like this click
and old and then you get to dock it
pretty much anywhere you want so this is
just like in normal dockable window I
like to dock mine at the very bottom
here the reason I like this layout so
much
because I have a lot of space to work in
3d here let's actually talk about this
first window here the scene window as
you can tell this one is split in two
there is a game window and also the
scene now the scene window is when you
do your editing that's when you're
placing objects in the scene that's when
you're just rotating stuff around and
we're going to be talking about that in
a second the game window is what happens
when you're playing so at this point
notice that I can't really move around
the same exact way as I did in the scene
window that is because when I'm in my
game view I'm using the game camera and
what I actually see in the game depends
on what I told my camera to see at so
right now I'm just going to drop an
object really quickly a cube and as you
can tell my camera is pointing towards
that cube if we go see in a game window
that is what we see so that's really the
big difference you're not able to move
in the game window unless you have some
game logic going on which we're gonna
have again a little bit later on right
so let's talk about actually navigating
through this 3d environment now if
you're familiar with the doom control a
really old game you can actually use
those control let me just explain really
quickly I have my mouse right here and I
hold my right click when I hold my right
click I'm able to just rotate around so
have a look around myself now using my
utter and I'll go on the WASD key and
I'll be able to move just like in a
flying FPS I guess I'm not sure if that
does exist but we're able to move and a
fly like this you're also able to move
around using your middle mouse so if you
just click and all the new your middle
Mouse as you can see I'm just dragging
this around now you also have a zoom out
and zoom in with your mouse again so you
can just practice navigating around here
a little bit you're going to be using
this window quite a lot and it's quite
fun when you're building your level when
you have some real assets going on so
maybe like a little threes little hill
boxes you can just place them around
super fast if you're used to those
controls right so let's talk about um
some more controls
you have in this window now something
I'm going to ask you to do really
quickly is go at the very top here click
on game object and then create a new
cube just like I did a second ago so
basically I've got a cube right now and
if you didn't see what I did right now
is I just move this to 0 0 0 and
position this is something I see in my
inspector and I will come back to that
in a moment as well so if I just click
on this now when selecting an object you
have a lot of keybinds that transfers
from the windows explorer to this so if
we just try and copy by doing a ctrl-c
and ctrl-v I don't know if you could
tell right here but we've got another
cube and if I just move this around like
this as you can tell there is now 2 if
we do control Z it moves back to the
position if we do it again it removes
the cube let's actually talk about
moving this around so as you can tell
right now I have a gizmo that allows me
to move this on the z axis on the x axis
and also on the y axis now quickly
notice that the y axis is actually up
and down it's not the z axis so in unity
the it's actually inverted with a lot of
softwares where the z axis would define
the height of the object now the reason
I have this gizmo is because I have an
object selected and I've press on W
which is if you just have a look at the
very top left side here you have some
options on your object and as you can
tell this is what you have by default
it's just a little hand where you can
just move around your scene when I press
W I go in the move gizmo so now I'm able
to move the object the next one is
rotation that you can also reach by
pressing on e on the keyboard and then
you can rotate around the x axis y axis
and z axis you can tell which axis it is
by the color so the red circle would
mean X the Z is blue and the Y is green
and after a scale there is one more
don't really use because I don't really
like to use unity in 2d is if we go into
the mode by just pressing that button
here or on the keyboard
it's the number two then if we go with
the last setting here which you can get
by pressing on T we're just pressing up
here you can modify the cube like this
as simple as it looks so it allows you
to actually modify things in 2d if we go
back in the 3d scene and we press on T
we'll still have the same exact option
but it's cool it's only going to allow
you to scale this on the X and y axis
not the z axis because it's meant for 2d
games and there really shouldn't be a
third axis in 2d so here it is that is
basic navigation and just one more thing
that I'd like to show you is when we
take our cube let's say we duplicate it
and we just move it on this side there
is actually a way to snap as you can see
it's not paying every single meter and
the way I do this is by moving it by
holding ctrl so this is a normal just
move and when I hold ctrl it actually
snaps one meter from where it was so you
can actually mess this up be just really
careful about that if you just move your
object like this and it's not really
sticking to the other one and you're all
day in control you're still going to be
a little bit offset as you can tell so
whenever you actually use this make sure
you know where you're starting from
right and if in case you just want to
make sure that those object touches like
this but maybe they're not the right
length for you for them to actually just
snap correctly right now they are you
can just duplicate this move this and as
you can tell they snap perfectly but
let's just say that the scale would be
something like 1.3 and then you'd
actually try to move that as you can
tell they overlap a little bit now there
is a way to snap on vertex and let me
just quickly show you how to do that
when you old V on the keyboard with your
move tool you actually snap on the
vertex and you can click say on this one
and you'd like this vertex to be
attached to this one this way there now
just stuck together so that's a pretty
good way to make a level without
actually having those little small gap
that might actually mess up your game
in the end depending on which technique
you use to say move your character or
check if there is the ground now notice
that every time I duplicate a cube or
every time I select something we have
just some action happening here in the
ir key now the R key is just a text
representation of your scene everything
you're going to be seeing in this 3d
environment is going to have a
definition right here on the ir key
right now my senior skull on title so we
don't really have a scene name this is
not saved and it still displays what
there is inside of it so let's just say
that I'm going to be a little bit crazy
and create a directional light another
one as you can tell there is now - there
is this guy here and also this guy here
and we can just select them using the R
key so just say that I'm looking for the
second directional light I can simply
double click on this one and it's going
to actually zoom on the object or so
that you're looking for your camera you
don't know where your camera is in the
scene you've been looking around for
like a good minute you can also find it
using the r key so as you can tell i
have my main camera selected now i can
double click on it and it shows it in
the view or i can click on f and it's
going to do the same exact thing so it
just goes back to my object like this
right so that's another way to actually
control the object you have in your
scene if you delete them from here say i
choose those two cubes i delete they're
also gone from the scene so just be
worried about that
those two are connected together that is
what you have to tell yourself right so
there is also one more thing connected
to these guys and as you can tell a
little bit earlier we played with it it
is the inspector on the right hand side
now the inspector is connected to a lot
of self annuity everything you select is
most likely going to have a definition
in the inspector so if we just have a
look here I'm going to select my camera
and then we have some information about
that camera so if we just check out this
component right here
it clears on the skybox it has a
different field of view which we can
modify it
a GUI layer audio listener all that kind
of good stuff and also a transform which
will contain the position we can modify
it at the very top right here and it's
going to be reflected inside of the game
we can also play with the rotation a
little bit as you can tell it also
reflects it in the game and they're just
connected together but now these things
we see on the right hand side they're
only for our selected object which is in
this case the camera if we were to
select the cube they actually change as
you can tell they're different stuff
that the camera doesn't really have so
the camera doesn't really have a box
Collider the camera doesn't really have
a mesh renderer but the cube does so as
you can tell the inspector changes its
definition what it puts inside the
inspector it changes with what you have
selected and now it's also going to be
changing for some other stuff as well
not only things in the scene if I just
give you a small example really quickly
I go inside the input manager now the
input manager is not something in the
scene but as you can tell it's been
drawn in the inspector so this doesn't
really have to do with anything right
now in my scene or our key and it's
still here so just be worried about that
when you click on something when you
select something and you're not sure
where you should be looking at to get
information about that say something
then make sure you check out the
inspector because what you're looking
for is most likely there all right so if
we just proceed the console down here is
what is going to be reporting some
errors so if your game crashes in the
middle of nowhere it's going to tell you
why so it's going to crash and it's also
going to tell you why
which one of code didn't work and also
maybe some warning that goes with that a
stack trace so you can go back in your
code and actually look ok so it did that
function well it did that other function
right after and then it crashed so it's
really going to be useful for debugging
it's really going to be useful for just
communicating with you when the game is
playing this is something we'll be using
quite a lot when we code and you're just
going to have a good time with it I
guess and finally the last window we're
going to be using is the
project window now this one I will leave
it right here for now we're not going to
be doing anything we're not going to be
talking about this one just for now
because I'll be reserving it for the
next episode it's quite a big window
we're going to be doing a lot of stuff
with that and there is a logic to be
made behind this window so we're just
going to leave it here for now and let's
quickly just wrap this tutorial up with
an exploration up here of the file menu
so at the very top here we have scenes
you can actually create a new scene save
a new scene now something that is really
important to know is one we're going to
be coding you don't really need to save
scenes because scene are not going to
contain information about the code you
write they're not going to be containing
information about the assets you create
those are going to be objects on their
own so in the Windows Explorer we're
going to be able to find those objects
they're not going to be really part of
the scene the only moment where you need
to change the scene is when you move
something around or when you change some
settings in the inspector so right now I
just create a new cube another one I can
save my scene the way I do this is by
hitting ctrl s and it's going to prompt
me right now the only reason it's
prompting me is because I never really
just created a scene in the first place
let me create my very first scene I'm
going to call it game and when I save
now it's going to be overriding game so
let's create a new cube and as you can
tell this scene is not really saved it's
not really up to date because the name
up here it says game and then it'll
stall the little style means that it's
not been saved if I press ctrl s the
star goes away now if I move something
around it goes back to being in a dirty
state where you have to save it again
right so that's pretty much all you have
to do when you save a scene really
simple we're going to be talking a
little bit more about scenes later on
and also build settings this is
something I'm going to skip for now now
in the Edit section there ain't much to
talk about except the preferences I
invite you to just open the Preferences
and have a look at the external tool for
this tutorial for this course I'm going
to be using Visual Studio to code but
you can also be using model develop I
really do recommend
you use Visual Studio though because Moo
develop is just starting to fail a
little bit and I think they're going to
drop it eventually just some rumor I
heard but still we're going to be using
Visual Studio on my side so if you just
want to see like matching colors and
helpings work in Visual Studio just make
sure it is on Visual Studio you can also
play with your color is a little bit
colors of uui change the color of axis
change the color of pretty much anything
and you have your key binds you can
modify and that is pretty much it the
rest we don't really care about right
now now the third option is asset we get
to create some kind of assets so this is
a lot of stuff you're going to be seeing
on the art side most likely we're also
going to be creating asset as
programmers because the scripts we're
going to be making are going to be
considered as assets but we're talking
here about materials we're talking about
models texture font but all that kind of
good stuff is actually considered as
assets so if you want to import those if
somebody else made it for you you can
actually import a package via this so
pretty much your whole game is going to
be made out of asset now since I've
installed unity with the standard asset
back which is something that just gave
you by default if you just check the
little button you can actually import
some package just to test it out as you
can tell right here I have you I have
the vehicle prototyping environment
let's actually import some in
environment just you check it out see
what they give us and how it works I'm
going to uncheck this just bring some
let's say we're going to be bringing
some water why not we can actually just
bring some water so I'm only going to
check water import and they're going to
be putting it in my project window which
I said we're going to be coming back to
that in a moment but as you can tell
without even doing anything in my game
I'm able to just use the asset that
they've made and here we go we have a
lake we have some kind of ocean actually
and this is all made for us this is
unity making a package and we simply
import it so a nice little flow of water
going on here now I'm going to remove
this because we're not going to be using
water in our game unfortunately it does
very good though now the next menu is
game object and this one I use quite a
lot so this is where you create some
prototyping objects since we don't
really have models for everything we're
like programmer and we're not really
good with art well I mean we're not the
best with art at least then you get to
create some nice basic cube like that
you get to create some nice planes some
quad all that kind of good stuff can be
created towards here you can also create
some lights some audio stores UI when
you're actually ready to create some UI
and also like camera particle system
there is a lot of stuff you can do here
you just create like a really base
object huge for prototyping there is
also other object that you're not going
to be using for prototype such as
delights all those one can be actually
final the particle system if you just
tweak it a little bit it can look quite
good and that is pretty much it now the
component I am NOT going to get into
this because this is a lot of stuff
we're going to be doing with code as
soon as we understand how to put it and
finally the window is just to pop your
windows back so if you just say you
delete your are key right here it's a
floating window now and you just click
on X you lose it you can find it back in
the window so as you can fill out right
here our key control for you pop it back
up and here you go you can actually just
put it back where it was like this so
this is where I'm actually going to end
the episode today we had a rough look at
how the engine actually just looks where
we can click how the windows work a
little bit it is not supposed to be like
something you understand right away
you're going to be understanding just by
practicing just by using it a lot so
guys thanks for watching I invite you to
watch the next episode which is going to
be about the assets and we're going to
be importing some cool stuff I'm going
to be looking at texture we're gonna be
looking at model scripts material a lot
of stuff so guys just make sure you tune
in also check out the channel subscribe
to the channel check out the patreon
page if you wish to just support me and
to support me making some more course
because I'm actually having quite a lot
of fun that's what I'm saying it's only
my first course but still um I'm having
quite a lot of fun so just check out the
patreon page
if you wish to quit so check out the
patreon page if you wish to support me
other than that please quit if you're
unable to support via patreon then just
leave a like on this video it helps
quite a lot you can also leave a comment
which is also going to help quite a lot
and I'll just make sure to just read all
of them and try to reply to your
question guys I have a lot of question
coming in but I do read every single one
of your comment and I'll do my best to
actually read them all for this video
specifically because it's the start of
the course so guys thanks for watching
again and I will see you next time