are already houses welcome back and in
this video series I am going to show you
how to make a Python web crawler now I
actually made this because a few weeks
ago I was trying to make a sitemap for
my website and if you guys don't know
what a sitemap is it's basically all the
links or all the pages on your website
so you need to make a program to crawl
your entire site and gather up all the
links and I'll search your non-line for
a free one and there aren't a lot of
good free ones they all like are limited
to like 50 pages or something and then I
was like are I'm just going to buy one
and all the ones that you can buy our
like a hundred bucks a year and I'm like
I'm not going to pay a hundred bucks a
year for a little bot that's going to
take like ten minutes to run so that was
my first motivation but I was lazy and I
didn't do it oh my god then I got a like
program this crawler and then a few days
ago I was looking through my website and
I was like you know what what would be
really cool is if you could have like
open source search engine for your own
website and I know that you can go ahead
and add like Google custom search
whenever you have a site and you want to
add some search to it but Google custom
search it doesn't really feel
comfortable like it's it kind of feels
like separate from your entire website
so I'm like man that crawler I was going
to make a few weeks ago that would been
a really nice so again all this program
is going to do in this video series is
basically going to go through all the
pages on your website and gather up all
the links so you can either use that for
a site map or if you're making like a
custom search engine then you can go
ahead and run some analytics on each
page later on but this is the core of a
lot of programs so that is my motivation
so let's go ahead and get started and
actually before I do that was a lie
we're not going to get started yet I
know that there are a couple armed
modules already in Python this is the
first one I looked at but this doesn't
even have Python 3 support yet I think
it's in beta and also this was a little
different from what I was trying to do
and I know that beautifulsoup does exist
but this is more of a parser so in other
words once you have HTML for example it
can like rip out the title and tell you
what the title of the page is
and you know maybe the content and all
the paragraphs and whatnot but again we
need to start with the basics we just
need to go ahead and gather the links
for your site before you can start
running analytics on all the pages so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to set
this up like we're going to use this a
bunch of times on a bunch of different
websites so let's say that I wanted to
run this on my website and my friend's
website and my uncle's I would need to
separate each of those into their own
different projects or own own different
folders so that's what we're going to do
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
first add a way where you can type in
something like the New Boston how can I
not type today alright so this is the
name of the project and then we can go
ahead and give the home page like this
again this isn't Python code I'm just
demonstrating how we're going to make it
so we'll say alright the project name is
the New Boston and this is your home
page so then it's going to go ahead and
create a folder and store all the links
in that folder and then they don't get
all jumbled together if you don't
understand what I'm talking about we'll
check this out so the first thing we're
going to do is we're going to import OS
and this is just actually want to kind
of keep that I kind of like that little
thing I don't know why all right so this
is just going to allow us to create
directories so let me say that on each
website you crawl is a separate project
and again the project files for this
it's not gonna be anything special a new
folder equals a new project simple as
that so we'll just call this function
def great project directory and then
we'll name it directory don't use the
keyword dir because dir is already a
built-in Python keyword so don't undo
that actually let me get rid of that
after all all right so the cool thing
about this program the way I made it is
I'm going to say go ahead and start off
by whenever we create a project for the
first time create that new folder for us
and start crawling the website
now let's say that your computer shuts
down maybe I know your electrical failed
or something or you just need to put
your computer to sleep or go home from
work or something you don't want to go
ahead and get rid of all that data let's
say it was like 50 percent done crawling
that you actually want to save that so
what I'm going to do is whenever you run
this again if that directory already
exists if that project already exists
we're not going to go ahead and create
it again we're just going to say ok only
create this if it doesn't exist
so we'll say if not OS dot path exists
and we'll see this is the path right
here so again the folder name is
essentially just the path only then do
we want to create a folder so I'm just
going to write a little prompt so
whenever they run this the user knows
what's going on I'll say creating
directory and then I'll print out the
name so my project name is going to be
the new Boston so whenever I run this
for the first time it's going to say
creating directory actually let me say
creating project that'll be a little bit
cooler a and then how do we actually
make it well it's the easiest thing ever
OS make directories and you just pass in
the directory name right there so let me
go ahead and run this right now show you
guys what's going on all right
so check this out you see how this load
directory doesn't have any folders or
anything and it just has main py the
file I'm working on right now so
whenever I run this bit of code what
it's going to do this is going to say
okay creating project the new Boston and
look at that we now got a folder called
the new Boston now let me go ahead and
run this again so say that we had some
data in here we're going to go ahead and
run it again you see how it didn't say
creating project in New Boston is
because it already created it so that
way it doesn't overwrite all of our
juicy files and also one thing I'm going
to do is I'm just going to change this
to general because this general file I'm
just going to have a lot of shared
functions in here and that main dot py
file that's kind of going to be the
starting point for our entire program so
I don't just don't want to pop these
right in there so again that's how our
projects gonna be set up that's what
we're doing in this video series and
yeah that's all I got to say I guess
I'll smell you guys later