our Rd houses welcome back and before we
begin I just want to give a quick shout
out to Jason a he is my third patron
donated five bucks to my patreon account
so Jason a thank you I love you all
right now I actually noticed whenever I
was editing the last video that I forgot
to use this forward slash because what
that would do is right now the file path
would be the new Boston a Q dot text and
of course we need the forward slash to
get the proper path just like that so
again make sure you add your little
forward slashes alright so let me just
go ahead and make sure that this works
first so what we're going to do whenever
you create the data files is it takes
two parameters as you see the first one
is the project name which is the new
Boston and the second one is the URL of
the home page so check this out whenever
I run this what it's going to do is you
see that this was empty before and we
now have two files so crawled which is
empty we didn't curl anything yet and
also the queue so we have one URL in the
waiting list so whenever our bots first
boots up it's going to say okay let me
get that in that's my starting point so
I can actually just go ahead and delete
this now and let me actually get rid of
this little thing all right so now I
actually just need to make a couple
other housekeeping functions like this
so this is for creating a brand new file
and we already saw when that's going to
be useful but later on what we're going
to do is we're going to be crawling a
lot of different pages and we don't want
to just create a brand new file each
time we're just going to discover more
links and we just want to add them onto
the end of this file right here
so we actually need a new function and
I'll just say a add data on to an
existing file so I'll say add F append
to file
and it will take the same parameters as
before what file would do you want to
pen - and what do you want to stick on
the end of it and for this you can
actually just go with open so you want
to open the file what file do you want
to open
well whatever one we tell you - and how
do you want to open it in a mode so a
means append or add onto the end of it W
means right so if you're writing a brand
new file and then we'll just say as file
so we have a reference to whatever file
we just open and now with the file we
can just call a write method and we'll
just say data and we'll go ahead and
stick a new line at the end so again
what we're going to do is we're
basically going to call this whenever we
want to stick a new link onto the end of
one of those files so it's going to
stick a link on it and then it's going
to bump the cursor down to the new line
or the pointer whatever you want to call
it and yeah then you have each link on a
new line I think it just looks a little
bit better that way now let me just make
another function called I'll say delete
all right so there are going to be times
where we actually want to clear or we
don't want to delete a file but we just
want to get rid of everything inside it
and we're going to see why this is
useful later on again I usually have
these in almost every single Python
program I write so these are really just
housekeeping but I'll say delete a file
contents and again you don't need any
data to be passed in here because you're
not writing it or appending anything
you're just deleting whatever's in there
so I'll say with open path this is
actually write mode Pass so basically
all we're doing right here is we're
creating a new file or overwriting the
existing one with the same name and this
path right here this is a key word that
you can use whenever you want to do
nothing
so it's essentially just the same of a
having a comment in just writing do
nothing but this is going to give you an
error because there's no code here so
whenever you just want to maybe have a
loop and have it do nothing then you can
just write pass
so again if a file exists instead of
just reading through every line in -
leaving it one by one we're just going
to create a file with the same name and
that's essentially just going to delete
all the contents in it alright now the
last two functions in here I'm actually
going to save for the next tutorial and
I'll tell you guys why but we got two
more functions to go for this file then
we get into the really fun stuff so see
you guys next time