alright guys I hope that you already
learn about functions because oh well
that's one we're going to teach you in
this video so if you're not well sucks
for you but anyways what the heck is a
function well whenever we make a big
computer program that's more than like
you know these small little samples that
we've been makin it's good to break your
program up into manageable chunks now
these chunks are called functions
alright so it helps organize our program
a little bit better pretty cool now
another cool thing about a function is
what we can do is we can write a certain
bit of code and put it inside a function
and then we can use it over and over
again whenever we want and however many
times you want really easily so I'll
show you guys how to make a really
simple function right now whenever you
make a function for the first time right
d e f this pretty much means you're
defining a function or creating a
function now after this you have to give
your function a name just like a
variable name and you can name it
anything you want I'll name it beef
because why the heck not just to show
you guys that it doesn't have to be
anything special now after the name add
parenthesis and I'll talk to you guys
about on what you can use the for later
on but for now we'll just put two empty
parenthesis and the last thing for your
definition is a colon now after this :
hit enter and any line of code that goes
in here is going to be part of your
function so any line of code that's
inside your function whenever you use it
later on this is the part that executes
so we'll make this a very simple
function print something out and we'll
just write they um
functions are cool alright so this is a
pretty useless function again this is
just a function called beef and the only
job of it is a print something out on
the screen so if you run this right now
okay nothing
print it out it's interesting and the
reason for that is this even though we
made a function right now we didn't tell
Python hey we actually want to use this
function so whenever you want to
actually use a function that you created
what you do is you type the name of your
function and then those two little
parentheses after so now when it gets to
this line it says okay
use a function called beef so then it
looks for a function called beef which
is this and it does whatever is inside
it so run it and check it out and like I
said before it the cool thing about
these is you can use them over and over
and over again as many times as you want
so this will call the function and
whenever I say caller function that's
just wait use a function means just a
technical stupid programmer talk calling
a function means using a function so I'm
calling beef three times simple enough
so now let me show you an actual useful
function and I also want to talk about
what these parentheses are right here so
we'll make a new function so underneath
it myself a little bit space write a new
function of course de f and I'll just
write like a Bitcoin to USD so what this
function is going to do is it's going to
take a Bitcoin amount and convert it to
US dollars so if you're curious about
like how many Bitcoin arm like how much
one bitcoins worth this function can do
that for you so inside these parentheses
right here whenever your function needs
extra information this is where it goes
so of course in order to calculate or
convert Bitcoin to US dollars it needs
the value of Bitcoin do you want to
convert one Bitcoin do you want to
convert 10 well it needs some extra
information so we're going to throw it
in as a variable and that variable is
going to be called B T C so now what we
need to do is just make the formula
so we will store the answer in amount
and we'll say the amount or the US
dollar amount it's equal to is however
many bitcoins multiplied by 527 so again
one Bitcoin would be 527 US dollars so
on and so forth so I guess we can just
print this out so print amount so again
in order to use this function what we do
is actually let me call p4 so I have
something when I post my source code on
the forum so this line is going to call
this function now this line is let's say
we want to convert like um we want to
see how many dollars three point eight
five bitcoins is so let me run this and
check it out this is the result of this
line and this is the result of this so
basically what we did is we called the
function and whenever we wrote three
point eight five in here it pretty much
took this value set it equal to the
variable BTC and anywhere in the
function that was BTC law BTC was
actually 3.85 so it took three point 8 5
x 5 27 and gave us the amount and then
if you want to say okay well what is it
for just one Bitcoin or what is it for
um I don't know like 13 bitcoins well if
you run this you can see one Bitcoin is
equal to 500 $27 13 bitcoins is equal to
almost $7,000 so it's a really awesome
way of taking a bit of code in being
able to reuse it incredibly easy so that
is all I have for you guys for functions
for right now we're going to be using
them a lot and if they seem confusing
right now then don't worry about it
because after we make a few more you're
going to become an expert of making them
so thing gas rushing don't
subscribe in I'll see you later