alright guys this is going to be a cool
tutorial because I'm going to show you
guys how to build a very simple program
where you can download an image from the
internet so the first thing I want to do
is import that random again and that's
because whenever we download an image
we're going to be giving it a random
filename and saving it as that because
we don't want to UM let so let's say we
were downloading like all the homepage
images we don't want a bunch of files
named homepage jpg in our directory so
I'm going to give each one a random name
and um whenever we build our web crawler
that's what we're going to do as well
and we're also going to be importing URL
Lib dot request now this is a package
that allows us to get um data from
websites pretty much that's a really
simple explanation and also I want to
mention this if I'm ever using a module
that you're like oh hold on a second um
you didn't tell me how to get that or
where I'm supposed to get that from or
what it does I'll explain that right now
whenever I have a module in here they
here that you're not familiar with go to
file settings and then if you go to your
project interpreter these words are hard
to say project interpreter on the Left
what you can do is this is the section
that allows you to download modules from
the internet so these are the ones that
I downloaded right now so say that we
wanted to add another one or install
another one click this little plus
button and you can search for all of
them right now now usually you know
exactly what one you're going to
download so if you start typing the name
of download like here's one I'm familiar
with um beautiful scraper right here
just select its name and hit install
package and then just sit back and relax
that's what's awesome about pycharm this
entire thing is built in the entire
module was just installed
you know whenever you want to use it we
can just import it right like this and
of course if you accidentally download a
one by accident or we're playing around
with it and figure it out you didn't
need it file settings the interpreter
and then just select it and hit this
minus sign
and that'll say that will uninstall it
basically so pretty cool but now back to
the tutorial so again I'm just going to
build a real simple function to go to
some on website download the image so
def download web image and the only
parameter that's going to take is just
the URL of the image of course so the
first thing I want to do is I want to
generate that random number just like we
did in the last tutorial so this is
going to be the name so I'm going to
story is the variable name and of course
you remember random dot R and range and
I'll just say one to a thousand so all
the images that we download are going to
be like 256 jpg arm like sixteen jpg so
on and so forth and this is um not the
best way but for this example it'll be
simple enough to follow along so now
what I want to do is whenever I download
it of course it's just going to be
stored as a number right here and
obviously what I want to do is add that
JPEG extension on the end so my computer
knows that it is indeed a jpg image so
full name will be the full file name and
of course we take that name which is a
random number one 1000 and what we're
going to do is we're going to add on the
dot jpg extension now remember before I
said that Python doesn't really like
when you take a number and add it to a
string so we need to convert this name
variable to a string and in order to do
that just put STR and this is a really
simple function that takes a number and
converts it into a string so now we're
working with the same data type now the
full name would be something like five
hundred jpg so the only other thing we
need to do one more line of code in this
function is download the image and of
course that's where we imported this so
in order to use anything from this
module type the name of the module which
is URL Lib dot request and the function
is called URL
retrieve now if you see it's going to
take a couple of parameters here the
first one is the URL of the website that
you're going to be downloading it from
pretty much um it's like going to be
HTTP on Bucky's room org slash Bucky's
face JPEG something like that so we're
going to be passing it in the function
so that's what the URL is and the second
parameter it takes is whenever we save
this or download it and save it to your
computer what do you want to name the
file well that's why we created this
right here so download this image and
save it as this on our computer so
that's all this function is doing right
here so now what we have to do is just
right download web image and we need to
pass it in a URL of some JPEG on the
internet so actually if you just go to
any site then I'm not going to show you
how to do that but it's all the same but
don't go to like a random site and say
hey Bucky told me to do this because
it's probably against their Terms of
Service but if you just want to practice
then you can just go - Bucky's room find
one of my images I'm on my profile right
now click view all photos and let's find
a don't want it down this is pretty dumb
all right so of course in order to get
the URL this you can just right click it
and hit copy image URL and of course
this pretty much is the URL of the image
on the internet so now back in our
program what we can do is remember to
pass it in as a string what we're saying
is basically download this image so it's
going to download it give it a random
filename and then save it to our
computer now it's going to download in
the same directory as our programs
around and so check this out this is my
main project YouTube and this was the
module from last tutorial and this is
where the program is going to run so
right now we only have two files main
and tuna but after we get done running
this we're also going to have an extra
jpg in here so keep your eyes on this
while I run it so check it out you see
how it just said 286 and
five just popped up well double-click
that and boom
pretty sweet we just downloaded an image
purely through Python programming so
just imagine the power of this we can
download a crapload of images in the
snap of a finger if we only knew how to
write a simple web crawler well ladies
and gentlemen that's what we had to look
forward to in the next tutorial but for
now thank you guys for watching don't
forget to subscribe and I'll see you
guys next time